<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Nature Vibration and Metamaterial RSS</title>
    <link>https://www.nature.com/search?q=(%22vibration%22+OR+%22vibrations%22)+AND+(%22metamaterial%22+OR+%22metamaterials%22)&amp;order=date_desc</link>
    <description>Latest vibration and meta articles from Nature</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 09:36:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic response of sandwich functionally graded nanoplate under thermal environments and elastic foundations using dynamic stiffness method</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-70210-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated discovery of reprogrammable nonlinear dynamic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-024-02008-6</link>
      <description>A framework is presented to automate the design of flexible metamaterial structures that can execute desired nonlinear dynamic tasks and have reprogrammable functionality.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active encoding of flexural wave with non-diffractive Talbot effect</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-73189-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composite metastructure with tunable ultra-wide low-frequency three-dimensional band gaps for vibration and noise control</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-73909-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and architecting of a broadband bullet-diamond shaped integrated frequency selective meta-surface absorber for aero-stealth platform</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-71559-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separating, purifying and decoding elastic waves by mimicking a cochlea on a thin plate</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01818-z</link>
      <description>Cochlea is a high-resolution auditory transduction organ to distinguish sounds in both high sensitivity and broadband working frequency. The authors mimic a cochlea on a plate, which can separate, purify and decode complicated elastic waves in quite a compact way.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-functional programmable active acoustic meta-device: acoustic switch, lens, and barrier</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-71737-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-chip phonon-enhanced IR near-field detection of molecular vibrations</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-53182-9</link>
      <description>Phonon polaritons can be harnessed for SEIRA spectroscopy. Here, the authors demonstrate a compact on-chip phononic SEIRA platform based on a h-BN/graphene/h-BN heterostructure atop a metal split-gate that serves both as a SEIRA substrate and as a room-temperature infrared detector.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A digitally embroidered metamaterial biosensor for kinetic environments</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-024-01263-4</link>
      <description>A textile metamaterial sensor can wirelessly measure biomarkers—such as heart rate and respiration—in vehicles and shows no accuracy degradation when operating in moving environments.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandgap formation mechanism in tacticity inspired elastic mechanical metastructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-75462-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable heat harvesting via thermal nonlinearity</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42254-024-00771-8</link>
      <description>This Perspective surveys the role of thermal nonlinearity in figures of merit through a multiscale physical understanding to advance heat harvesting technologies beyond linear processes, focusing on ‘nonlinear heat harvesting’, which potentially contributes to sustainable energy transition and decarbonization goals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neo-Hookean modeling of nonlinear coupled behavior in circular plates supported by micro-pillars</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-76528-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial biosensors for driver monitoring</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-024-01266-1</link>
      <description>Monitoring driver alertness could improve road safety, but the use of biosensors in moving vehicles is challenging. Now, a metamaterial biosensor has been designed that can be directly embroidered onto seat belts, enabling the contactless measurement of drivers’ vital signs. This biosensor shows reliable and consistent performance, even in challenging kinetic environments.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring smart hydrogels through manipulation of heterogeneous subdomains</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-53552-3</link>
      <description>Replicating the cellular structures in soft tissue has promise in the design of soft materials. Here, the authors report a hydrogel system with cellular patterns in which strain-driven heterogeneous subdomains are induced, allowing local and global behaviour to be tuned.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overdamping of vibration resonances by liquid crystal elastomers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-76952-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the study of solitary wave dynamics and interaction phenomena in the ultrasound imaging modelled by the fractional nonlinear system</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-75494-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandgap characteristics of four component periodic pile barriers in passive vibration isolation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-76735-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating new materials by turning failure on its head</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-03599-5</link>
      <description>Usually, materials either are stiff or can absorb shocks or vibrations; they rarely achieve both. A fresh approach combines these seemingly incompatible properties in materials that are at once stiff, lightweight and shock-absorbent. This technique embraces the failure of the materials.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Localized topological states beyond Fano resonances via counter-propagating wave mode conversion in piezoelectric microelectromechanical devices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-53925-8</link>
      <description>The authors introduce a MEMS device that leverages the destructive interference between two topological radiofrequency (RF) counter-propagating wave modes at a piezoelectric Aluminum Scandium Nitride (AlScN) Su-Schrieffer-Heeger (SSH) interface. This device offers enhanced sensing capabilities compared to conventional NEMS/MEMS, particularly for localized parameters such as the mass of a single cell.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing the topological pentagon states of a giant C540 metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-53819-9</link>
      <description>Fullerenes possess unique electronic property influenced by their real space topology and gauge field. Here, the authors construct an acoustic C540 fullerene metamaterial, allowing observation of 3D topological pentagon states using sound waves, and offering new insights into classical wave manipulation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-performance ultra-compact plasmonic metamaterial structure for optical THz absorption</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-77898-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model analysis and experiment study for effects of thermal viscous and fluid flow on ventilated acoustic metamaterials labyrinth</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-78454-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband surface enhanced infrared absorption with multiple Fano resonance by metallic oblique-wire-bundle metamaterial absorbers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-78633-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the directionality of membrane coupled Helmholtz resonators under open air conditions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-79568-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel gyroscope based on the slow surface acoustic wave in a phononic metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-024-00787-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust liquid crystal semi-interpenetrating polymer network with superior energy-dissipation performance</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-54233-x</link>
      <description>The design of liquid crystal networks as energy dissipation materials achieving simultaneously good mechanical and energy dissipation properties is challenging. Here, the authors fabricate energy-dissipation liquid crystal semi-interpenetrating polymer networks consisting liquid crystalline polymers with synergistic properties.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal imaging through hot emissive windows</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44172-024-00316-y</link>
      <description>It is not currently possible for an infrared camera to see through a hot window. Now Ciril Samuel Prasad and colleagues report a metasurface-coated window which suppresses thermal emission towards an IR camera while being sufficiently transparent for thermal imaging.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial-based Artificial magnetic conductor for efficient breast cancer diagnosis using a low-cost antenna array</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-79666-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomimetic optoelectronics with nanomaterials for artificial vision</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-024-00750-6</link>
      <description>Inspired by biological systems, artificial vision technologies have advanced considerably, particularly with the development of curved image sensors, which improve visual data capture, and neuromorphic optoelectronics, which enable efficient in-sensor processing. This Review provides a comprehensive discussion of current nanomaterial-based biomimetic optoelectronics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives of chiral nanophotonics: from mechanisms to biomedical applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44310-024-00045-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanics of Drosophila wing deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-54527-0</link>
      <description>Upon emerging from their pupal case, insects swiftly deploy their wings from a compact origami-like structure to a fully extended blade. Here, authors use a combination of imaging and mechanical tests to model the kinematics and dynamics of wing deployment in Drosophila.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heavy-boundary mode patterning and dynamics of topological phonons in polymer chains and supramolecular lattices on surfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-54511-8</link>
      <description>Topological phonon boundary modes (TBM) hold promises for advanced phononic applications. Here, the authors introduce the bulk-heavy boundary correspondence to pattern TBM in polymers and supramolecular assemblies under thermal fluctuations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the digital–physical divide using haptic and wearable technologies</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-024-01325-7</link>
      <description>This Review examines the development of haptic and wearable technologies that could be used to build a more realistic and immersive metaverse, exploring the potential applications of such technology and the ethical and technological challenges that the field faces.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of nickel and copper shells on mechanical properties of advanced lightweight TPU metamaterials during uniaxial compression</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-82317-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimaterial cryogenic printing of three-dimensional soft hydrogel machines</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-55323-6</link>
      <description>Hydrogel-based machines have potential in a range of applications, but it can be challenging to prepare multimaterial devices with complex structures. Here, the authors report the development of a multimaterial cryogenic printing technique that can be used to prepare three-dimensional structures with geometries such as overhanging, thin-walled and hollow.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid electromagnetic and moisture energy harvesting enabled by ionic diode films</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-55030-2</link>
      <description>Wireless energy-responsive systems are essential for intelligent devices. This study demonstrates an electromagnetic-moist coupling effect for energy harvesting and signal transmission using fabricated ionic diode films, showing improved performance and potential for practical applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the intrinsic piezoelectric anisotropy of tetragonal ABO3 perovskites through a high-throughput study</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41524-024-01496-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of melt and glass states of halide perovskite semiconductors</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-024-00759-x</link>
      <description>Crystalline metal halide perovskites have garnered substantial recent research attention given their outstanding semiconducting character, unprecedented tunability and wide-range application. This Perspective highlights the exciting prospects of extending this focus beyond long-range order — that is, to glassy and melt states.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of parallel coiled cavities of different depths in microperforated panel sound absorbers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-85171-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electret integrated magnetic field sensor based on magnetostrictive polymer composite with nT resolution</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-85069-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All-angle unidirectional flat-band acoustic metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-55937-4</link>
      <description>Flat bands have empowered novel phenomena such as canalization, high-collimation and low-loss propagation. Here, the authors propose the concept of symmetry broken moiré systems, which overcomes the limitations of fixed flat bands, enabling multiple and unidirectional canalizations.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reverse design of broadband sound absorption structure based on deep learning method</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-86077-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly sensitive split ring resonator-based sensor for quality monitoring of edible oils</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-85800-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-objective design of multi-material truss lattices utilizing graph neural networks</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-86812-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On quantifying dynamic behavior of architected metal/polymer TPMS/lattices-based interpenetrating phase composites</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-84303-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning optimized design of THz piezoelectric perovskite-based biosensor for the detection of formalin in aqueous environments</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-88766-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and modeling of a highly compact negative index floral shape metamaterial for flight navigation applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-88612-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composite acoustic system for low-frequency sound absorption</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-89151-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: Breaking the silence - the launch of npj Acoustics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44384-025-00002-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the low-frequency band gap characteristics of longitudinal vibration of ship shafting based on bionic quasi-zero stiffness metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-89986-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
