<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Nature Vibration Metamaterials RSS</title>
    <link>https://www.nature.com/search?q=%28%22vibration%22+OR+%22vibrations%22%29+AND+%28%22metamaterial%22+OR+%22metamaterials%22%29&amp;order=date_desc&amp;page=1</link>
    <description>Latest articles from Nature with both "vibration/vibrations" and "metamaterial/metamaterials"</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 07:03:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Subcycle control of terahertz waveform polarization using all-optically induced transient metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/lsa201436</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soft plasmons with stretchable spectroscopic response based on thermally patterned gold nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep04182</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective impedance boundary optimization and its contribution to dipole radiation and radiation pattern control</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms4188</link>
      <description>Controlling sound waves is important to build better acoustic devices, and much can be learnt from optical approaches. To this end, Quan et al.show how periodic arrays of Helmholtz resonators on metal plates can produce dipole-like radiation patterns for sound.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Locomotion of microspheres for super-resolution imaging</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep03501</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sound and heat revolutions in phononics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nature12608</link>
      <description>The phonon is the physical particle responsible for the transmission of sound and heat; controlling the properties of phonons in materials could trigger many advances, which are reviewed here.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A general strategy for the DNA-mediated self-assembly of functional nanoparticles into heterogeneous systems</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nnano.2013.209</link>
      <description>Nanoparticles with plasmonic, magnetic, catalytic and luminescent properties can be self-assembled into heterogeneous superlattices with the help of DNA.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting secondary structure and surface orientation of helical peptide monolayers from resonant hybridization signals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep02956</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-enhanced molecular spectroscopy (SEMS) based on perfect-absorber metamaterials in the mid-infrared</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep02865</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontiers in terahertz sources and plasmonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2013.235</link>
      <description>The development of innovative tools and techniques is vital for improving research capabilities and opening up new research directions in the terahertz regime. Terahertz sources and plasmonics are just two examples of current exciting advances.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new twist on terahertz pulses</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2013.236</link>
      <description>The generation of light pulses with programmable waveforms opens up exciting new avenues for coherent control. Researchers in Japan have now introduced a way to tailor the polarization state of custom-shaped terahertz pulses at the push of a button.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Acoustic Wavefront by Inhomogeneous Impedance and Steerable Extraordinary Reflection</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep02537</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Observation of Negative Effective Gravity in Water Waves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep01916</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Casimir forces on a silicon micromechanical chip</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms2842</link>
      <description>The Casimir effect is based on quantum electrodynamical effects between two electrically neutral objects in close proximity. Here Zou et al. observe the Casimir effect between two silicon components on a single micromechanical chip, allowing for an on-chip exploitation of the Casimir force.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic rainbow trapping</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep01728</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly evolved grains</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat3609</link>
      <description>By efficiently exploring the huge variety of possible grain shapes, computer algorithms that mimic evolution make possible the design of grains that pack into configurations with the desired mechanical or structural properties.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic Illusion near Boundaries of Arbitrary Curved Geometry</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep01427</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene plasmonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2012.262</link>
      <description>Many researchers hope to merge plasmonics and graphene photonics to combine their useful features. The properties and characteristics of plasmons on graphene are reviewed. Prospects for possible future applications are discussed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast acousto-magneto-plasmonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2012.220</link>
      <description>Surface plasmon polaritons have become popular because of their sub-wavelength confinement and the possibility to perform ultrasensitive optical measurements. This article reviews the development of active plasmonic devices and new metrologies using hybrid multilayer structures combining with the magnetic, acoustic and ultrafast effects.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large-area high-throughput synthesis of monolayer graphene sheet by Hot Filament Thermal Chemical Vapor Deposition</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep00682</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectral selectivity in infrared thermal detection</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/lsa201224</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chirality of matter shows up via spin excitations</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphys2387</link>
      <description>Chirality is usually manifested by differences in a material’s response to left- and right-circularly polarized light. This difference is the result of the specific distribution of charge within chiral materials. A similar response has now been found to result from the chiral spin structure of an antiferromagnet.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimode circuit optomechanics near the quantum limit</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms1993</link>
      <description>Optomechanical systems allow for the exploration of macroscopic behaviour at or near the quantum limit. Masselet al. use micromechanical resonators to study the hybridisation of one photonic and two phononic modes with phonon numbers down to 1.8, showing a coupling between all three degrees of freedom.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmonics in the mid-infrared</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2012.161</link>
      <description>Plasmonics can be used to enhance mid-infrared sources, sensors and detectors for applications such as chemical sensing, thermal imaging and heat scavenging. The challenge now is to integrate these technologies in cost-effective, compact and reliable platforms.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical metamaterials with negative compressibility transitions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat3331</link>
      <description>Most materials expand along the direction of an external pulling force, but there are no materials that compress instead. The proposal of mechanical metamaterials that show such negative compressibility promises new artificial materials with designed functionalities.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dark acoustic metamaterials as super absorbers for low-frequency sound</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms1758</link>
      <description>Metamaterials can be used to alter the transmission of light or sound, with their tailored structures permitting control over their optical or acoustic properties. Meiet al. present a thin-film acoustic metamaterial that provides efficient absorption of sound over a broad range of wavelengths.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fano-resonant asymmetric metamaterials for ultrasensitive spectroscopy and identification of molecular monolayers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat3161</link>
      <description>Plasmonic nanostructures are known to be an attractive platform for highly sensitive molecular sensors, although they often lack specificity. A plasmonic device with a sharp optical resonance tuned to biomolecules selectively captured on the surface of the device now offers a versatile yet highly specific platform for molecular sensing.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coherent terahertz control of antiferromagnetic spin waves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2010.259</link>
      <description>Researchers report the direct observation of ultrafast magnetic dynamics using the magnetic component of highly intense terahertz wave pulses with a time resolution of 8 fs. This concept provides a universal ultrafast method of visualizing magnetic excitations in the electronic ground state.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A holey-structured metamaterial for acoustic deep-subwavelength imaging</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphys1804</link>
      <description>A three-dimensional periodic structure focuses acoustic waves to a spot size that is one fiftieth of the wavelength—beating the classical diffraction limit by a long way. The device could lead to improved resolution for ultrasound imaging.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coherent mixing of mechanical excitations in nano-optomechanical structures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2010.5</link>
      <description>Nanocavity optomechanical systems can exhibit strong dynamical back-action between mechanical motion and the cavity light field. Here, optical control of mechanical motion within two different nanocavity structures is demonstrated. A form of optically controlled mechanical transparency is also demonstrated, which is analogous to electromagnetically induced transparency.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Properties and emerging applications of self-assembled structures made from inorganic nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nnano.2009.453</link>
      <description>Self-assembly is a powerful technique for controlling the structure and properties of ensembles of inorganic nanoparticles. This article reviews the properties and potential applications of self-assembled structures made from nanoparticles.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental demonstration of an acoustic magnifying hyperlens</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat2561</link>
      <description>Like their optical counterparts, acoustic metamaterials are capable of manipulating sound waves in unusual ways. An acoustic hyperlens is now demonstrated that is capable of magnifying subwavelength acoustic waves, and could therefore find applications in medical imaging or underwater sonar.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our choice from the recent literature</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2009.147</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterials: Ideal focus</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/459504a</link>
      <description>Before they were touted as invisibility cloaks, metamaterials promised a perfect lens. Geoff Brumfiel reports on the struggle for superior vision.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This issue</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2008.183</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coding drugs...tuning friction...and there's more...</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat2078</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This issue</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat2079</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cutting-edge terahertz technology</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2007.3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of Structural Phase Transition in VO2 by Epitaxial Strain in Vicinity of Metal-insulator Transition</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep23119</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass Separation by Metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep21971</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of conductive reduced graphene oxide into microstructured optical fibres for optoelectronics applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep21682</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solitary Wave in One-dimensional Buckyball System at Nanoscale</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep21052</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling sound with acoustic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/natrevmats20161</link>
      <description>Acoustic metamaterials can be used manipulate sound waves with a high degree of control. Their applications include acoustic imaging and cloaking. This Review outlines the designs and properties of these materials, discussing transformation acoustics theory, anisotropic materials and active acoustic metamaterials.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purcell effect and Lamb shift as interference phenomena</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep20599</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Individual speckle diffraction based 1D and 2D Random Grating Fabrication for detector and solar energy harvesting applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep20501</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband non-reciprocal transmission of sound with invariant frequency</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep19824</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum algorithms: an overview</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/npjqi201523</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forests as a natural seismic metamaterial: Rayleigh wave bandgaps induced by local resonances</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep19238</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All-dielectric metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nnano.2015.304</link>
      <description>This Review discusses recent research efforts to confine and guide light at the nanoscale without using metals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-scale photonic hybrids for mid-infrared and terahertz nanophotonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nnano.2015.305</link>
      <description>This Perspective discusses materials that can sustain hybrid surface plasmon and surface phonon polaritons for future nanophotonics applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spinning top-ology</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat4522</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bio-inspired heterogeneous composites for broadband vibration mitigation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep17865</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scattering-type scanning near-field optical microscopy with reconstruction of vertical interaction</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms9973</link>
      <description>Conventionally, scattering-type scanning near-field optical microscopy does not provide information on the vertical characteristic of near-field responses. Here, Xu et al. develop a method to reconstruct the vertical interaction response between the tip and the sample using this near-field technique.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Measurement of Optical Force Induced by Near-Field Plasmonic Cavity Using Dynamic Mode AFM</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep16216</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The antisymmetry of distortions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms9818</link>
      <description>In a material system, a distortion constitutes a change from one stable state to another via a pathway built from a combination of atomic trajectories. Here, the authors present a distortion reversal antisymmetry operation which fully describes the symmetry of such pathways.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time-Domain Filtering of Metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep16737</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly sensitive and selective sugar detection by terahertz nano-antennas</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep15459</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantiomeric switching of chiral metamaterial for terahertz polarization modulation employing vertically deformable MEMS spirals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms9422</link>
      <description>Spectroscopy in the terahertz range requires polarization modulation. Here, Kan et al.demonstrate a chirality switchable metamaterial for polarization modulation employing deformable spirals. A polarization rotation as high as 28° is achieved, providing a practical and compact polarization modulator for the terahertz range.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical study of achiral phase-change metamaterials for ultrafast tuning of giant circular conversion dichroism</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep14666</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snapping metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat4439</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A density-independent rigidity transition in biological tissues</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphys3471</link>
      <description>Cells moving in a tissue undergo a rigidity transition resembling that of active particles jamming at a critical density—but the tissue density stays constant. A new type of rigidity transition implicates the physical properties of the cells.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial Absorber for Electromagnetic Waves in Periodic Water Droplets</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep14018</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water: Promising Opportunities For Tunable All-dielectric Electromagnetic Metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep13535</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial Absorbers for Infrared Detection of Molecular Self-Assembled Monolayers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep12570</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbolic phonon-polaritons in boron nitride for near-field optical imaging and focusing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms8507</link>
      <description>Hyperbolic phonon polariton modes in natural hyperbolic materials could have uses in near-field optical imaging, guiding, and focusing applications. Here Li et al.demonstrate enlarged imaging and super-resolution focusing from a flat slab of hexagonal boron nitride enabled by hyperbolic phonon polariton modes.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene on hexagonal boron nitride as a tunable hyperbolic metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nnano.2015.131</link>
      <description>The amplitude and wavelength of hyperbolic phonon polaritons in hexagonal boron nitride can be tuned using a monolayer graphene gate.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dispersionless Manipulation of Reflected Acoustic Wavefront by Subwavelength Corrugated Surface</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep10966</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Through-space transfer of chiral information mediated by a plasmonic nanomaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nchem.2280</link>
      <description>Surface-enhanced resonant Raman optical activity (SERROA) reveals the through-space transfer of chirality from biomolecules to achiral benzotriazole dye-conjugated nanotags. The chiroptical responses generated by the stereoisomers of ribose and tryptophan establish this as the basis for a stereoselective nanosensor platform.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fano resonance boosted cascaded optical field enhancement in a plasmonic nanoparticle-in-cavity nanoantenna array and its SERS application</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/lsa201569</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic modulation of infrared radiation in graphene plasmonic resonators</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms8032</link>
      <description>Graphene’s exotic properties make it suitable for many different optoelectronic devices. Brar et al. show that graphene plasmonic resonators can be exploited to produce narrow spectral emission in the mid-infrared, whose frequency and intensity can be modulated by electrostatic gating.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Athermally photoreduced graphene oxides for three-dimensional holographic images</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms7984</link>
      <description>Owing to its electronic and optical properties, graphene holds potential for flat display systems. Here, Li et al. write wide-angle, full-colour, three-dimensional holographic images using subwavelength, multilevel index modulation of athermally reduced graphene oxide by a single femtosecond pulse.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subdiffractional focusing and guiding of polaritonic rays in a natural hyperbolic material</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms7963</link>
      <description>Hexagonal boron nitride has many interesting properties, including a natural hyperbolic dispersion, making it attractive for nanophotonic applications. Here, Dai et al. show that metallic disks under the material launch phonon–polaritons, turning it into a hyper-focusing lens.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous mirror-symmetry breaking in coupled photonic-crystal nanolasers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2015.65</link>
      <description>The observation of symmetry breaking in a coupled nanolaser system could yield new types of switchable devices.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waveform Selectivity at the Same Frequency</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep09639</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of Ordered Mullite Nanowhisker Array with Surface Enhanced Raman Scattering Effect</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep09690</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mid-infrared nanophotonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat4252</link>
      <description>The confinement and scattering lifetimes of graphene plasmons are improved when graphene is sandwiched between layers of thin hexagonal boron nitride. This finding should pave the way for nanophotonic applications in the low-loss regime.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband Lamb Wave Trapping in Cellular Metamaterial Plates with Multiple Local Resonances</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep09376</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to deal with the loss in plasmonics and metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nnano.2014.310</link>
      <description>Metal losses affect the performance of every plasmonic or metamaterial structure; dealing with them will determine the degree to which these structures will find practical applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbolic phonon–polaritons</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat4149</link>
      <description>Hexagonal boron nitride nanostructures are shown to sustain phonon–polariton modes with comparable performances to plasmon–polariton modes in graphene but with lower losses.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refractometric biosensing based on optical phase flips in sparse and short-range-ordered nanoplasmonic layers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/lsa2014101</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacing whispering-gallery microresonators and free space light with cavity enhanced Rayleigh scattering</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep06396</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Angular momentum-induced circular dichroism in non-chiral nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms5922</link>
      <description>The differential absorption of left and right handed light, circular dichroism, is typically observed only in chiral objects. Here, the authors demonstrate that giant circular dichroism can be induced in non-chiral objects when the left and right handed circularly polarized modes used are vortex beams.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origami based Mechanical Metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep05979</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid fabrication of hierarchically structured supramolecular nanocomposite thin films in one minute</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms5053</link>
      <description>There is significant research into fabrication methods for the rapid, scalable preparation of composite nanomaterials. Here, the authors probe the assembly of supramolecular nanocomposites in thin films and are able to optimize parameters to produce hierarchically structured thin films in one minute.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic metasurface with hybrid resonances</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat3994</link>
      <description>Acoustic impedance-matched surfaces do not reflect incident waves. Traditional means of acoustic absorption have so far resulted in imperfect impedance matching and bulky structures, or require costly and sophisticated electrical design. Inspired by electromagnetic metamaterials, a subwavelength acoustically reflecting surface with hybrid resonances and impedance-matched to airborne sound at tunable frequencies is now demonstrated.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectral interferometric microscopy reveals absorption by individual optical nanoantennas from extinction phase</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms4748</link>
      <description>Absorption by an optical nanoantenna determines its interaction strength with light, yet this quantity is hidden from conventional spectroscopy. Gennaro et al. now demonstrate a spectroscopic technique that reveals a nanoantenna’s absorption by recovering its amplitude and phase response.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platonic Scattering Cancellation for Bending Waves in a Thin Plate</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep04644</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bose–Einstein condensation in an ultra-hot gas of pumped magnons</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms4452</link>
      <description>In contrast to real atoms, Bose–Einstein condensation of quasi-particles does not require low temperature, but is obtained via external pumping. Here, the authors show an unexpected transitional dynamics of a Bose–Einstein condensate of magnons due to a nonlinear evaporative supercooling mechanism.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optical Measurement of In-plane Waves in Mechanical Metamaterials Through Digital Image Correlation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep42437</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wave-based liquid-interface metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms14325</link>
      <description>Here, Francoiset al. propose a method of remotely shaping particle trajectories by using rotating waves on a liquid gas interface. The superposition of orthogonal standing waves creates angular momentum which is transferred from waves to floating microparticles, guiding them along closed trajectories.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta-Optical Chirality and Emergent Eigen-polarization Modes via Plasmon Interactions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep40718</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material-assisted metamaterial: a new dimension to create functional metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep42076</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling thermal emission of phonon by magnetic metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep41858</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Deflecting elastic prism” and unidirectional localisation for waves in chiral elastic systems</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-00054-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme terahertz science</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2016.249</link>
      <description>In the future, sources of intense terahertz radiation will open up an era of extreme terahertz science featuring nonlinear light–matter interactions and applications in spectroscopy and imaging.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineered metabarrier as shield from seismic surface waves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep39356</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imaging electric field dynamics with graphene optoelectronics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms13704</link>
      <description>Detection of electric fields, central to chemical and biological processes, has been limited to measurements of current (e.g., electrodes) and secondary reporters (e.g., fluorescent dyes). Here, the authors demonstrate an optical platform capable of imaging electric field dynamics with high spatio-temporal resolution.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All-Silicon Ultra-Broadband Infrared Light Absorbers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep38589</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanomechanical motion transduction with a scalable localized gap plasmon architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms13746</link>
      <description>Flexible approaches are required for building plasmomechanical devices for tunable optical devices. Here, Roxworthyet al. introduce a plasmonic-nanoelectromechanical systems device where gap plasmon resonators are embedded into arrays of moving silicon nitride nanostructures, yielding thousands of devices per chip.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The quasiparticle zoo</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphys3977</link>
      <description>Quasiparticles are an extremely useful concept that provides a more intuitive understanding of complex phenomena in many-body physics. As such, they appear in various contexts, linking ideas across different fields and supplying a common language.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low frequency piezoresonance defined dynamic control of terahertz wave propagation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep38041</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonreciprocity and magnetic-free isolation based on optomechanical interactions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms13662</link>
      <description>Nonreciprocal components are widely used in optical circuits but the magneto-optic effects they are based on pose difficulties for on-chip integration. Here, Ruesink et al. propose an optomechanical scheme to break reciprocity without the need for magnetic fields.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modified relaxation dynamics and coherent energy exchange in coupled vibration-cavity polaritons</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms13504</link>
      <description>Vibration-cavity polaritons are mixed states produced by strong coupling between a vibrational mode and an optical cavity. Here, the authors show that these polaritons can coherently exchange energy and exhibit drastically altered transient spectra and dynamics compared to uncoupled vibrations.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polarization bandgaps and fluid-like elasticity in fully solid elastic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms13536</link>
      <description>Controlling elastic waves in medium is essential to many applications in mechanical to earthquake engineering. Ma et al. demonstrate selective suppression of different vibrational modes in a three-dimensional rod-shape structure, which shows fluid-like elasticity with only longitudinal waves propagating.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental demonstration of anomalous Floquet topological insulator for sound</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms13368</link>
      <description>Topological protected acoustic wave propagation has been predicted, but yet awaits for experimental demonstration. Here, Peng et al. report one-way propagation of pseudo-spin-dependent edge states for sound, analogous to Floquet topological insulator in solid state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced flexural wave sensing by adaptive gradient-index metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep35048</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmonic metamaterial absorber for broadband manipulation of mechanical resonances</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2016.183</link>
      <description>Coherent mechanical oscillations are optically driven on a metamaterial absorber that has a voltage-tunable Fano resonance. Inversely, optical damping of the mechanical resonance is also achieved.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable sound transmission at an impedance-mismatched fluidic interface assisted by a composite waveguide</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep34688</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic omni meta-atom for decoupled access to all octants of a wave parameter space</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms13012</link>
      <description>For meta-atoms, achieving full access to the wave parameter space remains a problem. Here, Koo et al. outline the criteria for the decoupling of wave parameter from first principles, and realize an omni meta-atom that achieves independent, broad-range access to all octants of acoustic parameter space.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quasi-static stop band with flexural metamaterial having zero rotational stiffness</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep33410</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmonic nanoantenna hydrophones</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep32892</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverse Doppler Effects in Broadband Acoustic Metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep32388</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial-enhanced vibrational absorption spectroscopy for the detection of protein molecules</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep32123</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogel microphones for stealthy underwater listening</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms12316</link>
      <description>Conventional ceramic SONAR suffers from large acoustic impedance mismatch with water, rendering them easily detectable. Here, Gao et al. report a new design using a hydrogel filled with stimuli-responsive metal nanoparticles, which detects low-frequency sound with a high-sensitivity and zero-reflection.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral light intrinsically couples to extrinsic/pseudo-chiral metasurfaces made of tilted gold nanowires</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep31796</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanolithography using Bessel Beams of Extreme Ultraviolet Wavelength</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep31301</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape morphing Kirigami mechanical metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep31067</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tunable acoustic metamaterial with double-negativity driven by electromagnets</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep30254</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological mechanics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphys3801</link>
      <description>Electronic topological insulators have inspired the design of new mechanical systems that could soon find real-life applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced optical gradient forces between coupled graphene sheets</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep28568</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical investigation of band gaps in 3D printed cantilever-in-mass metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep28314</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elastic metamaterials for tuning circular polarization of electromagnetic waves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep28273</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic one-way metasurfaces: Asymmetric Phase Modulation of Sound by Subwavelength Layer</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep28023</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optical transduction and routing of microwave phonons in cavity-optomechanical circuits</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2016.107</link>
      <description>Researchers demonstrate microwave phonon waveguide circuits and tunable delay and filter for microwave-photonics signals carried by 1,500 nm wavelength light.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneously Assembled Metamaterials and Metadevices via 3D Modular Transfer Printing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep27621</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A seismic metamaterial: The resonant metawedge</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep27717</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brillouin scattering self-cancellation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms11759</link>
      <description>The interaction between light and acoustic phonons is radically modified in sub-wavelength photonic structures. Here, the authors engineer the optical and acoustic modes to perfectly cancel the two interaction mechanisms—the photo-elastic and moving-boundary effects—which leads to Brillouin self-cancellation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tensional acoustomechanical soft metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep27432</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible optical switching of highly confined phonon–polaritons with an ultrathin phase-change material</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nmat4649</link>
      <description>Optically rewritable surface phonon–polariton resonators are demonstrated in a system combining phase-change materials that can reversibly switch between amorphous and crystalline phases, with polar crystals that support surface phonon–polaritons.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Localized surface plasmon enhanced photothermal conversion in Bi2Se3 topological insulator nanoflowers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep25884</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformation seismology: composite soil lenses for steering surface elastic Rayleigh waves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep25320</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Printed Reversible Shape Changing Components with Stimuli Responsive Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep24761</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal frequency shift and tunable microwave absorption in BiFeO3 family</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep24837</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmonic piezoelectric nanomechanical resonator for spectrally selective infrared sensing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms11249</link>
      <description>Plasmonic metasurfaces can provide exciting optical functionalities. Here, Hui et al. demonstrate an infrared sensor by combining plasmonic and piezoelectric electromechanical resonances, demonstrating efficient transduction of vibration with a strong and polarization-independent absorption over an ultrathin thickness.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradient Index Devices for the Full Control of Elastic Waves in Plates</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep24437</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cymatics for the cloaking of flexural vibrations in a structured plate</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep23929</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optical modulators with 2D layered materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2016.15</link>
      <description>The recent realization that 2D layered materials could modulate light with superior performance has prompted intense research and significant advances, paving the way for realistic applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elastic metamaterials for independent realization of negativity in density and stiffness</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep23630</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kirigami-based Elastic Metamaterials with Anisotropic Mass Density for Subwavelength Flexural Wave Control</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-18864-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dial-in Topological Metamaterials Based on Bistable Stewart Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-18410-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Hermitian physics and PT symmetry</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphys4323</link>
      <description>This Review Article outlines the exploration of the interplay between parity–time symmetry and non-Hermitian physics in optics, plasmonics and optomechanics.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological guiding of elastic waves in phononic metamaterials based on 2D pentamode structures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-18394-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flat lens effect on seismic waves propagation in the subsoil</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-17661-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron nitride nanoresonators for phonon-enhanced molecular vibrational spectroscopy at the strong coupling limit</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/lsa2017172</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Features of electronic and lattice mechanisms of transboundary heat transfer in multilayer nanolaminate TiAlN/Ag coatings</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-17291-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photomechanical meta-molecule array for real-time terahertz imaging</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/micronano201771</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Route to Terahertz Metamaterial Biosensor Integrated with Microfluidics for Liver Cancer Biomarker Testing in Early Stage</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-16762-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergent wave phenomena in coupled elastic bars: from extreme attenuation to realization of elastodynamic switches</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-16364-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-centered Double-slit Metamaterial for Elastic Wave Polarization Anomaly</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-15746-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phononic Crystal Waveguide Transducers for Nonlinear Elastic Wave Sensing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-14594-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-low and ultra-broad-band nonlinear acoustic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-00671-9</link>
      <description>Linear acoustic metamaterials based on resonances are generally tunable but limited by their narrow bands. Here, Fang et al. fabricate one- and two-dimensional nonlinear acoustic metamaterials with a broadband, low-frequency, response—greatly suppressing low frequency noise.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconfigurable systems for multifunctional electronics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41528-017-0009-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microparticles controllable accumulation, arrangement, and spatial shaping performed by tapered-fiber-based laser-induced convection flow</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-14802-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wave Manipulations by Coherent Perfect Channeling</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-14422-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible mechanical metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/natrevmats201766</link>
      <description>Mechanical metamaterials exhibit exotic properties that cannot be realized in conventional materials. In this Review, recently developed shape-morphing, topological and nonlinear metamaterials are discussed together with their functionalities and design principles, and future challenges for the field are outlined.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband dual-anisotropic solid metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-13322-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced terahertz fingerprint detection with ultrahigh sensitivity using the cavity defect modes</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-13612-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Optical and Surface Enhanced Raman Scattering properties of Ag modified silicon double nanocone array”</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-12423-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conical Refraction of Elastic Waves by Anisotropic Metamaterials and Application for Parallel Translation of Elastic Waves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-10691-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light-sound interconversion in optomechanical Dirac materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-09942-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic-control multifunctional acoustic metasurface for reflected wave manipulation at deep subwavelength scale</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-09652-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing out-of-plane deformation to design 3D architected lattice metamaterials with tunable Poisson’s ratio</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-09218-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano metamaterials for ultrasensitive Terahertz biosensing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-08508-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-controlled wave propagation in hyperelastic media</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-08098-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stretching Micro Metal Particles into Uniformly Dispersed and Sized Nanoparticles in Polymer</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-07788-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-temperature crystallization of nanocrystals into three-dimensional superlattices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nature23308</link>
      <description>A bottom-up process to achieve rapid growth of micrometre-sized three-dimensional nanocrystal superlattices during colloidal synthesis at high temperatures is revealed by in situ small-angle X-ray scattering; the process is applicable to several colloidal materials.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced sensing and conversion of ultrasonic Rayleigh waves by elastic metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-07151-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium Dioxide Engineered for Near-dispersionless High Terahertz Permittivity and Ultra-low-loss</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-07019-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A diatomic elastic metamaterial for tunable asymmetric wave transmission in multiple frequency bands</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-05526-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active KTaO3 hybrid terahertz metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-05529-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystalline metamaterials for topological properties at subwavelength scales</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms16023</link>
      <description>Existing classical wave analogues of topological insulator are physically wavelength scaled, limiting potential applications. Here, Yveset al. show complex topological crystalline properties in spatially ordered metamaterials with deep subwavelength resonant elements on specific lattices.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conformable Holographic Metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-04482-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-transmission acoustic self-focusing and directional cloaking in a graded perforated metal slab</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-04512-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single phase 3D phononic band gap material</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-04235-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferroelectric-assisted gold nanoparticles array for centimeter-scale highly reproducible SERS substrates</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-03301-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Polarized Surface-Enhanced Infrared Spectroscopy by Fano-Resonant Asymmetric Metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-03545-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Optical Forces in InP-Based Waveguides</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-03409-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoimaging of resonating hyperbolic polaritons in linear boron nitride antennas</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms15624</link>
      <description>Here, the authors report a near-field study of hyperbolic phonon polaritons in linear antennas made of hexagonal boron nitride. Infrared nanospectroscopy and nanoimaging experiments reveal sharp Fabry-Perot resonances with large quality factors, exhibiting atypical modal behaviour.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial-inspired silicon nanophotonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nphoton.2017.39</link>
      <description>Applying metamaterial concepts to dielectric systems offers low losses compared with metallic structures. Here, silicon-based metamaterial and nanophotonic advances are reviewed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nontrivial nonradiating all-dielectric anapole</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-01127-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental evidence of Fano resonances in nanomechanical resonators</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-01147-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optical manipulation from the microscale to the nanoscale: fundamentals, advances and prospects</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/lsa201739</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable Nanoantennas for Surface Enhanced Infrared Absorption Spectroscopy by Colloidal Lithography and Post-Fabrication Etching</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep44069</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sound Insulation in a Hollow Pipe with Subwavelength Thickness</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep44106</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-time monitoring and visualization of the multi-dimensional motion of an anisotropic nanoparticle</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep44167</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid acoustic metamaterial as super absorber for broadband low-frequency sound</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep43340</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband gradient impedance matching using an acoustic metamaterial for ultrasonic transducers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/srep42863</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static non-reciprocity in mechanical metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nature21044</link>
      <description>Suitably engineered mechanical metamaterials show static non-reciprocity—that is, the transmission of motion from one side to the other depends on the direction of that motion.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmonic mid-infrared third harmonic generation in germanium nanoantennas</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-018-0108-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near-zero effective impedance with finite phase velocity for sensing and actuation enhancement by resonator pairing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-018-07697-7</link>
      <description>In spite of extensive studies on zero-index metamaterials, the realization of zero impedance with finite phase velocity has not been explored. Here, the authors show that this extreme case, realized by elaborately-tuned paired resonators, can effectively enhance sensing and actuation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance metrics and enabling technologies for nanoplasmonic biosensors</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-018-06419-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic tweezers for the life sciences</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-018-0222-9</link>
      <description>This review discusses and contrasts different acoustic-tweezer technologies and their applications in biology.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of acoustomechanical instability and bifurcation behavior of soft materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-34971-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-plane anisotropic and ultra-low-loss polaritons in a natural van der Waals crystal</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-018-0618-9</link>
      <description>Observation of the anisotropic propagation of polaritons along the surface of layered, semiconducting α-MoO3 confirms the existence of this phenomenon in natural materials.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-018-0061-4</link>
      <description>Sound waves can be manipulated using structurally designed 2D materials of subwavelength thickness. This emerging field, namely, acoustic metasurfaces, is driven by the desire to control acoustic wave propagation using compact devices.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High permittivity processed SrTiO3 for metamaterials applications at terahertz frequencies</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-33251-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damping of selectively bonded 3D woven lattice materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-32625-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abnormal Stop Band Behavior Induced by Rotational Resonance in Flexural Metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-32597-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superstructures generated from truncated tetrahedral quantum dots</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-018-0512-5</link>
      <description>Truncated tetrahedral nanocrystals can self-assemble into one-, two- and three-dimensional superstructures.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-way Acoustic Beam Splitter</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-29579-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optically-active metastable defects in volumetric nanoplasmonic composites</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-30803-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring far-infrared surface plasmon polaritons of a single-layer graphene using plasmon-phonon hybridization in graphene-LiF heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-31049-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic cloak based on Bézier scatterers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-30888-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterials with amplitude gaps for elastic solitons</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-018-05908-9</link>
      <description>Here, the authors experimentally observed, numerically simulate, and mathematically analyze the existence of amplitude gaps for elastic vector solitons in highly deformable mechanical metamaterials consisting of rigid units and elastic hinges.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deformation mechanism of innovative 3D chiral metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-30737-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active-Tuning and Polarization-Independent Absorber and Sensor in the Infrared Region Based on the Phase Change Material of Ge2Sb2Te5 (GST)</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-30550-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wave propagation in tunable lightweight tensegrity metastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-29816-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconfigurable and tunable twisted light laser</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-29868-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The heat is on</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-018-0226-0</link>
      <description>The generation of hot electrons in plasmonic nanostructures is of scientific and technological interest, putting the community under pressure to better understand the hot-electron mechanisms and to increase the light conversion efficiency of plasmonic nanosystems for chemical reactions and photodetection.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband Bending of Flexural Waves: Acoustic Shapes and Patterns</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-29192-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoplasmonic optical antennas for life sciences and medicine</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-018-0033-8</link>
      <description>Nanoplasmonics have emerged as a promising technology for applications in life sciences and medicine. In this Review, we discuss the application of nanoplasmonic optical antennas for in vivo intracellular exploration, photonic gene delivery and regulation, and in vitro molecular diagnostics.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering polymer MEMS using combined microfluidic pervaporation and micro-molding</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-018-0017-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-material Additive Manufacturing of Metamaterials with Giant, Tailorable Negative Poisson’s Ratios</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-26980-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passive temperature control based on a phase change metasurface</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-26150-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Band transition and topological interface modes in 1D elastic phononic crystals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-24952-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bilayer synergetic coupling double negative acoustic metasurface and cloak</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-24231-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of elastic topological states in soft materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-018-03830-8</link>
      <description>Here the authors present an experimental observation of topological states in soft elastic metamaterials. They show reversibility in topological phases by changing filling ratio, tension and/or compression, while also demonstrating tunability of topological interface states by mechanical deformation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-chip temporal focusing of elastic waves in a phononic crystal waveguide</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-018-03726-7</link>
      <description>Here the authors demonstrate the temporal control of ultrasonic wave propagation in a one-dimensional phononic crystal waveguide. Four-wave mixing experiments are implemented, providing a platform on which to realize novel nonlinear phenomena in the system.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effective way</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-018-0050-4</link>
      <description>A theoretical framework for the design of so-called perturbative metamaterials, based on weakly interacting unit cells, has led to the experimental demonstration of a quadrupole topological insulator.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal management and non-reciprocal control of phonon flow via optomechanics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-018-03624-y</link>
      <description>Phonon transport control is important for thermal and non-reciprocal devices. Here, Seif et al. combine heat transport in nanostructures and optomechanics into a platform for manipulating phonons with which they design an acoustic isolator and a thermal diode.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electromagnetic wave absorption and compressive behavior of a three-dimensional metamaterial absorber based on 3D printed honeycomb</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-23286-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards anti-causal Green’s function for three-dimensional sub-diffraction focusing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-018-0082-3</link>
      <description>A metamaterial-based acoustic sink has been designed to serve the purpose of absorbing the diverging waves and demonstrating three-dimensional sub-diffraction spherical sound wave focusing.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver and ultrasmall iron oxides nanoparticles in hydrocolloids: effect of magnetic field and temperature on self-organization</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-22426-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Input-Independent Energy Harvesting in Bistable Lattices from Transition Waves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-22003-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoexcitation circular dichroism in chiral molecules</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-017-0038-z</link>
      <description>Photoexcitation circular dichroism generates an ultrafast response in chiral molecules, with a much higher sensitivity than standard circular dichroism.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untethered soft robotics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-018-0024-1</link>
      <description>This Review Article examines the development of functional untethered soft robotics, evaluating recent advances in soft robotic actuation, sensing, and integration in relation to untethered systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Escaping the Ashby limit for mechanical damping/stiffness trade-off using a constrained high internal friction interfacial layer</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-20670-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband single-phase hyperbolic elastic metamaterials for super-resolution imaging</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-20579-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D auxetic single material periodic structure with ultra-wide tunable bandgap</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-19963-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anderson light localization in biological nanostructures of native silk</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-02500-5</link>
      <description>Light in biological media is known as freely diffusing because interference is negligible. Here, the authors demonstrate Anderson localization of light from quasi-two-dimensional nanostructures in silk fibres.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of an acoustic superlens using single-phase metamaterials with a star-shaped lattice structure</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-19374-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A facile synthesis of porous graphene for efficient water and wastewater treatment</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-19978-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-efficiency electroluminescence and amplified spontaneous emission from a thermally activated delayed fluorescent near-infrared emitter</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-017-0087-y</link>
      <description>Near-infrared organic light-emitting diodes that operate in the 700 nm region with an external quantum efficiency of almost 10% are reported.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light induced assembly and self-sorting of silica microparticles</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-19282-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape-matching soft mechanical metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-19381-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing perturbative metamaterials from discrete models</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-017-0003-3</link>
      <description>A perturbative method is proposed for the systematic design of mechanical metamaterials, where each element of the discrete model is associated with individual geometric features of the metamaterial, through the weak interaction between the unit cells.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of a phononic quadrupole topological insulator</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/nature25156</link>
      <description>A two-dimensional phononic quadrupole topological insulator is demonstrated experimentally using mechanical metamaterials, which has both the one-dimensional edge states and the zero-dimensional corner states predicted by theory.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous topological insulators constructed from random point sets</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-017-0024-5</link>
      <description>Whether spatial order is required for structures that support topological modes remains unclear. Amorphous arrangements of interacting gyroscopes suggest that topology arises in materials for which the only design principle is the local connectivity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically reconfigurable architected materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-019-1538-z</link>
      <description>Architected silicon-based lattices are reported that reversibly transform their structure on electrochemical lithiation and delithiation, through cooperatively coupled buckling instabilities that are sensitive to random  and  pre-designed defects.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damped resonance for broadband acoustic absorption in one-port and two-port systems</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-49222-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moebius strips of chiral block copolymers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-11991-3</link>
      <description>The Moebius topology is intriguing because of its structural elegance and distinct properties. Here the authors report block copolymer Moebius strips via a fast self-assembly of chiral block copolymer polystyrene-block-poly(D-lactide acid) in tetrahydrofuran/water mixed solvents.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near-field acoustic manipulation in a confined evanescent Bessel beam</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-019-0191-z</link>
      <description>The development of photonics and plasmonics has seen electromagnetic evanescent waves being used for diverse applications from trapping small particles to illumination in biological applications. As an equivalent to the optics counterpart, the authors report on the generation of an acoustic evanescent Bessel field for acoustofluidic applications that only requires a single piezoelectric element in a sub-wavelength resonant cavity and that can be used to attract or repel particles and cells using acoustic radiation force.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near-Field Scanning Microwave Microscopy in the Single Photon Regime</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-48780-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brillouin integrated photonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-019-0498-z</link>
      <description>Acousto-optical interactions within integrated optics platforms are reviewed with a discussion of the useful chip-based devices such as lasers, amplifiers, filters, isolators and more besides that can result.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional resonating metamaterials for low-frequency vibration attenuation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-47644-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin Planar Metasurface-based Acoustic Energy Harvester with Deep Subwavelength Thickness and Mechanical Rigidity</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-47649-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbolic plasmon–phonon dispersion on group velocity reversal and tunable spontaneous emission in graphene–ferroelectric substrate</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41699-019-0112-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-parallel resonators to increase the absorption of subwavelength acoustic absorbers in the mid-frequency range</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-47516-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoscale nonreciprocity via photon-spin-polarized stimulated Raman scattering</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-11175-z</link>
      <description>Here, the authors introduce and study theoretically and numerically a scheme for breaking time-reversal symmetry and achieving nonreciprocity on the nanoscale, using spin-selective stimulated Raman scattering. These results could pave the way for compact nonreciprocal communication and computing technologies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launching of hyperbolic phonon-polaritons in h-BN slabs by resonant metal plasmonic antennas</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-11143-7</link>
      <description>Momentum mismatch prevents efficient coupling between free space photons and hyperbolic phonon polaritons. The authors show, using far-field infrared spectroscopy, infrared nanoimaging and numerical simulations, that resonant metallic antennas can efficiently launch hyperbolic phonon polaritons in thin h-BN slabs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic meta-atom with experimentally verified maximum Willis coupling</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-10915-5</link>
      <description>Willis coupling is an additional degree of freedom, which can enhance acoustic metamaterials, by coupling monopole and dipole excitations. Here, the authors experimentally demonstrate a meta-atom with Willis coupling approaching the theoretical maximum, which is robust to thermo-viscous losses.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photonics with hexagonal boron nitride</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-019-0124-1</link>
      <description>Hexagonal boron nitride (hBN) is highly sought after for mid-IR nanophotonics, nonlinear and quantum optics, and as an efficient UV emitter. This Review surveys its fundamental physical properties, applications and synthesis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal design of lattice structures for controllable extremal band gaps</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-46089-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designer photonic dynamics by using non-uniform electron temperature distribution for on-demand all-optical switching times</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-10840-7</link>
      <description>Here, the authors engineer a non-uniform electron temperature distribution through nanostructuring and demonstrate a sub-300 fs switching time. This can assist in the design of nanostructures for nonlinear optics, hot carrier extraction and photocatalysis</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terahertz circular dichroism spectroscopy of biomaterials enabled by kirigami polarization modulators</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-019-0404-6</link>
      <description>Kirigami metamaterials show significant terahertz circular dichroism and are adopted as tunable optical elements in the terahertz region.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phononic integrated circuitry and spin–orbit interaction of phonons</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-10852-3</link>
      <description>Developing planar phononic circuits analogous to photonic circuits are of interest to provide scalable advantages and complex manipulation of phonons. Here, the authors realize a phononic integrated circuit with a Gallium Nitride-on-sapphire platform, which provides strong confinement and control of phonons.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological Optimization of Phononic Crystal Thin Plate by a Genetic Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-44850-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kirchhoff’s metasurfaces towards efficient photo-thermal energy conversion</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-44781-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustofluidic separation of cells and particles</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-019-0064-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shell-type acoustic metasurface and arc-shape carpet cloak</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-44619-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low frequency 3D ultra-wide vibration attenuation via elastic metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-44507-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fano Metamaterials on Nanopedestals for Plasmon-Enhanced Infrared Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-44396-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoS2 with Organic Fragment - a New Hybrid Material for Laser Writing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-44085-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the thermal conductivity in hexagonal boron nitride via controlled boron isotope concentration</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-019-0145-5</link>
      <description>Hexagonal boron nitride has been theoretically predicted to have high values for its thermal conductivity which would make it useful for thermal management of devices but these values have not been experimentally achieved. The authors manipulate the isotope concentration of B to increase the thermal conductivity and reach these predicted values.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lensing in the Ultrasonic Domain using Negative Refraction Induced by Material Contrast</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-42655-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Casimir metrology platform with a commercial MEMS sensor</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-019-0054-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of spatiotemporally tailored terahertz wavepackets by nonlinear metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-09811-9</link>
      <description>While the terahertz range has become increasingly important for a wide range of applications, efficient sources with bespoke output characteristics are still lacking. Here, Keren-Zur et al. show that engineering of a metasurface’s individual elements allows control of the spatiotemporal properties of the emitted terahertz radiation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon-enhanced light–matter interactions and applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41524-019-0184-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wave attenuation and trapping in 3D printed cantilever-in-mass metamaterials with spatially correlated variability</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-41999-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry for mechanics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-019-0500-1</link>
      <description>The mechanics of many materials can be modelled by a network of balls connected by springs. A bottom-up approach based on differential geometry now captures changes in mechanics upon network growth or merger, going beyond the linear deformation regime.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme nanophotonics from ultrathin metallic gaps</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-019-0290-y</link>
      <description>This Review discusses the origins of localized plasmon resonances in few-nanometre or sub-nanometre gaps between metal nanoparticles and metal films, as well recent experimental observations and potential future directions.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable Superconducting Cavity using Superconducting Quantum Interference Device Metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40891-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near-zero metamaterial inspired UHF antenna for nanosatellite communication system</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-40207-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological phases in acoustic and mechanical systems</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42254-019-0030-x</link>
      <description>This Review describes topological phenomena that can be realized in acoustic and mechanical systems. Methods of symmetry breaking are described, along with the consequences and rich phenomena that emerge.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic tunneling with CNT-based metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-39325-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Printed Microwave Metamaterial-Antenna Circuitries on Nickel Oxide Polymerized Palm Fiber Substrates</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-39736-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Negative reflection of elastic guided waves in chaotic and random scattering media</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-38480-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible controls of broadband electromagnetic wavefronts with a mechanically programmable metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-38328-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Evidence of Rainbow Trapping and Bloch Oscillations of Torsional Waves in Chirped Metallic Beams</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-37842-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical requirements and inverse design for broadband perfect absorption of low-frequency waterborne sound by ultrathin metasurface</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-37510-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating microsystems with metamaterials towards metadevices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-018-0042-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The evolving unity of physics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42254-018-0007-1</link>
      <description>Modern theoretical physics is indivisible. Ideas flow freely and fruitfully across traditional boundaries separating materials physics, fundamental physics and cosmology. How did this state of affairs come to be? What are its outstanding results? Is there more to come? Frank Wilczek discusses the synergy between the different fields of physics.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deeply subwavelength phonon-polaritonic crystal made of a van der Waals material</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-018-07795-6</link>
      <description>Photonic crystals can steer, shape, and sculpture the flow of photons. Here, the author fabricate a deep-subwavelength photonic crystal slab that supports ultra-confined phonon polaritons, by patterning a nanoscale hole array in h-BN.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of higher-order topological acoustic states protected by generalized chiral symmetry</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-018-0252-9</link>
      <description>The physics of a second-order topological insulator, such as two-dimensional polarization, one-dimensional edge states and zero-dimensional corner states, are demonstrated experimentally in an acoustic breathing kagome lattice.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological sound</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-018-0094-4</link>
      <description>For both fundamental and applied sciences topological states of matter is an area of intense research and most investigations are dedicated to realizing these materials using electronic and optical methods. Here the authors review recent efforts in a third avenue of research which seeks to emulate topological states using acoustics.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband sound barriers with bianisotropic metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-018-07809-3</link>
      <description>Methods to silence broadband noise and shield large volumes are lacking. Here, the authors show theoretically and experimentally that acoustic bianisotropic materials, with non-zero strain to momentum coupling, lead to effective sound barriers with excellent efficiency in terms of attenuation, bandwidth, and shielded volume.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terahertz integrated electronic and hybrid electronic–photonic systems</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-018-0173-2</link>
      <description>This Review Article examines the development of terahertz integrated electronic and hybrid electronic–photonic systems, considering, in particular, advances that deliver important functionalities for applications in communication, sensing and imaging.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental realization of on-chip topological nanoelectromechanical metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-018-0764-0</link>
      <description>Topological nanoelectromechanical metamaterials are realized at the micrometre scale, using silicon nitride nanomembranes, opening the way for on-chip integrated acoustic components in high-frequency signal-processing applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-range nonspreading propagation of sound beam through periodic layered structure</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-020-00422-1</link>
      <description>Recently dispersion-free propagation of spatiotemporally-modulated optical pulses over long distances has been demonstrated, but acoustic analogues are less well-explored. Here, anomalous dispersion and strong anisotropy is demonstrated for the long-distance non-spreading propagation of acoustic waves through an underwater metamaterial.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subwavelength broadband sound absorber based on a composite metasurface</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-70714-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An active mechanical Willis meta-layer with asymmetric polarizabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-17529-2</link>
      <description>Here, the authors experimentally demonstrate abilities of a mechanical Willis meta-layer, in beams and plates, for independently engineering transmission and reflection coefficients of flexural waves in both amplitude and phase and nonreciprocal wave propagation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental proof of emergent subharmonic attenuation zones in a nonlinear locally resonant metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-68894-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive tuning of infrared emission using VO2 thin films</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-68334-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonreciprocity in acoustic and elastic materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-020-0206-0</link>
      <description>Nonreciprocal acoustic and elastic wave propagation may enable the creation of devices such as acoustic one-way mirrors, isolators and topological insulators. This Review presents advances in the creation of materials that break reciprocity and realize robust, unidirectional acoustic and elastic wave steering.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macroscopic manifestation of domain-wall magnetism and magnetoelectric effect in a Néel-type skyrmion host</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41535-020-0247-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis and observation of the breakdown of Babinet’s principle in complementary spoof surface plasmon polariton structures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-67923-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual frequency sound absorption with an array of shunt loudspeakers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-67810-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband thin sound absorber based on hybrid labyrinthine metastructures with optimally designed parameters</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-67688-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cochlea-inspired design of an acoustic rainbow sensor with a smoothly varying frequency response</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-67608-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailored elastic surface to body wave Umklapp conversion</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-17021-x</link>
      <description>Umklapp scattering, an effect that has been conventionally studied in phonon systems in quantum transport, is studied here in an elastic system. The authors demonstrate mode conversion from surface Rayleigh waves into bulk waves that have uniquely tunable properties.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emulating tightly bound electrons in crystalline solids using mechanical waves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-67108-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active structural acoustic illusions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-66398-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near Zero Index Perfect Metasurface Absorber using Inverted Conformal Mapping</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-66476-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological polaritons and photonic magic angles in twisted α-MoO3 bilayers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2359-9</link>
      <description>The photonic dispersion of phonon polaritons in bilayers of α-phase molybdenum trioxide can undergo tunable topological transitions at magic interlayer twist angles.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attosecond science based on high harmonic generation from gases and solids</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-16480-6</link>
      <description>Different methods are demonstrated in recent years to produce attosecond pulses. Here, the authors discuss recent development and future prospects of the generation of such pulses from gases and solids and their potential applications in spectroscopy and ultrafast dynamics in atoms, molecules and other complex systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common-path interferometric label-free protein sensing with resonant dielectric nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-020-0336-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four-dimensional metal-organic frameworks</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-16527-8</link>
      <description>As the field of metal-organic frameworks is maturing, understanding the dynamics of open frameworks is progressing and rational approaches are under development. Here, the authors outline challenges and potential routes to engineering the spatio-temporal evolution of dynamic metal-organic frameworks.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable photo-responsive elastic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-16272-y</link>
      <description>Here, the authors present a light-responsive elastic metamaterial whose transmission spectrum can be tuned by light stimuli. More specifically, we demonstrate that an appropriate laser illumination is effective in reversibly widening an existing frequency band gap, doubling its initial value.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excitation of Faraday-like body waves in vibrated living earthworms</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-65295-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic field induced nonlinear magneto-optical rotation in a diamond mechanical resonator</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-65049-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Micromorphic Beam Theory for Beams with Elongated Microstructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-64542-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Randomized resonant metamaterials for single-sensor identification of elastic vibrations</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-15950-1</link>
      <description>Designing efficient and flexible metamaterial with uncorrelated transmissions for spatial vibration encoding and identification remains a challenge. Here, the authors propose a randomized resonant metamaterial with randomly coupled local resonators for single-sensor identification of elastic vibrations.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental understanding and applications of plasmon-enhanced Raman spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42254-020-0171-y</link>
      <description>Plasmon-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (PERS) is a highly sensitive technique that can provide molecular fingerprint information. This Technical Review discusses the fundamental principles, advantages and limitations of PERS, key issues in using PERS and interpreting results, and state-of-the-art applications in materials characterization, bioanalysis and the study of surfaces.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-speed femtosecond laser plasmonic lithography and reduction of graphene oxide for anisotropic photoresponse</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-020-0311-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear increase, invisibility, and sign inversion of a localized fs-laser-induced refractive index change in crystals and glasses</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-020-0298-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous roll-to-roll patterning of three-dimensional periodic nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-020-0133-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From bulk to molecularly thin hybrid perovskites</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-020-0185-1</link>
      <description>Owing to their layered structure, the properties of 2D perovskites can be controlled by tuning their thickness. This Review surveys how fine-tuning the thickness of 2D perovskites from the sub-micrometre to the molecularly thin regime helps to optimize their electrical and optical properties for use in different applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Van der Waals thin films of WTe2 for natural hyperbolic plasmonic surfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-15001-9</link>
      <description>Hyperbolic plasmonic surfaces supporting highly directional propagating plasmon-polaritons have been realized in artificial metamaterials. Here, the authors demonstrate experimentally a hyperbolic plasmonic surface naturally occurring in thin films of WTe2, a type-II Weyl semimetal with layered structure.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of Non-aliased Two-dimensional Acoustic Vortex with Enclosed Metasurface</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-60836-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasensitive detection of saccharides using terahertz sensor based on metallic nano-slits</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-60732-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The stiffness of living tissues and its implications for tissue engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-019-0169-1</link>
      <description>The complexity of biological tissue presents a challenge for engineering of mechanically compatible materials. In this Review, the stiffness of tissue components — from extracellular matrix and single cells to bulk tissue — is outlined, and how this understanding facilitates the engineering of materials with lifelike properties is discussed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduced micromorphic model in orthogonal curvilinear coordinates and its application to a metamaterial hemisphere</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-59696-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact Nonlinear Acoustic Diode</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-59270-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dualities and non-Abelian mechanics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-1932-6</link>
      <description>Dualities—mathematical mappings between different systems—can act as hidden symmetries that enable materials design beyond that suggested by crystallographic space groups.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexural band gaps and response attenuation of periodic piping systems enhanced with localized and distributed resonators</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-56724-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel microscale selective laser sintering (μ-SLS) process for the fabrication of microelectronic parts</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-019-0116-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimensional hierarchy of higher-order topology in three-dimensional sonic crystals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-13333-9</link>
      <description>Here, the authors report the experimental discovery of such a dimensional hierarchy of the topologically-protected 2D surface states, 1D hinge states and 0D corner states in a single 3D acoustic system by using higher-order topological sonic crystals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanochemical synthesis of carbon-stabilized Cu/C, Co/C and Ni/C nanocomposites with prolonged resistance to oxidation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-54007-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collective dynamics of strain-coupled nanomechanical pillar resonators</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-13309-9</link>
      <description>Here, the authors demonstrate strain-induced, strong coupling between two adjacent nanomechanical pillar resonators for the investigation of collective dynamical phenomena. Both mode hybridization and the formation of an avoided level crossing in the response of the nanopillar pair are experimentally observed.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active control on switchable waveguide of elastic wave metamaterials with the 3D printing technology</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-52705-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schools of skyrmions with electrically tunable elastic interactions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-12723-3</link>
      <description>While flocking and schooling are more often associated with birds and fish, these types of behaviour can also be observed in inanimate systems. Here the authors demonstrate schooling of topological solitons in a liquid crystal system powered by oscillating electric fields.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of subnanometric phonon modes in a plasmonic nano-cavity via ambient tip-enhanced Raman spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41699-019-0121-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-reciprocal robotic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-12599-3</link>
      <description>Here, the authors demonstrate a robotic metamaterial implemented through a combination of actuators, sensors and local controllers. They show that this active metamaterial can exhibit tunable linear non-reciprocal dynamic characteristics, with a very large and broadband non-reciprocal gain.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tacticity in chiral phononic crystals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-12587-7</link>
      <description>Here, the authors study the influence of tacticity on the dynamic behaviour of chiral structured periodic media comprising rotational inertia elements. This opens the way towards new mechanisms for wave control by exploiting spin-spin coupling mechanism.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study of Abnormal Group Velocities in Flexural Metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-50146-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocrystal superlattices as phonon-engineered solids and acoustic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-12305-3</link>
      <description>Phonon engineering enables tailored heat-transfer properties, controlled elastic and acoustic vibration propagation, and custom phonon-electron and phonon-photon interactions. Here, the authors present an approach for the observation and tunability of vibrational modes of nanocrystal superlattices.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial colloidal liquid metacrystals by shearing microlithography</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-11941-z</link>
      <description>Stable periodic structures can be difficult to obtain in a liquid crystal compared to a solid due to the energetic instability of the former. Here the authors present a technique to fabricate quasicrystalline structures of graphene oxide liquid crystals which have high stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substrate-integrated photonic doping for near-zero-index devices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-12083-y</link>
      <description>Here, the authors demonstrate substrate-integrated photonic doping, enabling the implementation of near-zero-index media within a printed circuit board integrated design. They illustrate the potential by designing and numerically demonstrating a dielectric sensor, an acousto-microwave modulator and a flexible transmission line.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexural band gaps and vibration control of a periodic railway track</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-97384-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and alignment of liquid crystalline elastomers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-021-00359-z</link>
      <description>Liquid crystalline elastomers are stimuli-responsive polymeric materials whose mechanical properties can be programmed by patterning their local orientation, making them promising candidates to serve as low-density actuators and functional elements in various applications. This Review discusses the synthesis and processing of liquid crystalline elastomers, with a focus on alignment methods and potential applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ghost hyperbolic surface polaritons in bulk anisotropic crystals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03755-1</link>
      <description>Hyperbolic phonon polaritons that exhibit long-distance, ray-like propagation and oblique wavefronts are described at the surface of an anisotropic bulk crystal.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergent order in hydrodynamic spin lattices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03682-1</link>
      <description>A macroscopic analogue of a spin system is shown to emerge in an ensemble of droplets bouncing on the surface of a vibrating bath, revealing symmetry-breaking phenomena such as ‘magnetic’ ordering.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoscale terahertz scanning probe microscopy</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-021-00835-6</link>
      <description>Recent progress in terahertz scanning probe microscopy is reviewed with an emphasis on techniques that access length scales below 100 nm relevant to material science. An outlook on the future of nanoscale terahertz scanning probe microscopy is also provided.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust topological designs for extreme metamaterial micro-structures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-94520-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneity-stabilized homogeneous states in driven media</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-24459-0</link>
      <description>Spontaneous symmetry breaking can induce instabilities in natural and engineered systems. Nicolaou et al. show that such instabilities can be prevented by introducing suitable system asymmetry in the form of spatial heterogeneity, relevant for the development of novel control and design techniques.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Brillouin–Mandelstam light-scattering spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-021-00836-5</link>
      <description>Nearly 100 years after the prediction of Brillouin light-scattering spectroscopy, or Brillouin–Mandelstam light-scattering spectroscopy, the effect has proved itself a powerful tool for decades. Now its application to probing confined acoustic phonons, phononic metamaterials and magnons is reviewed.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterials for simultaneous acoustic and elastic bandgaps</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-94053-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning and computation-enabled intelligent sensor design</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-021-00360-9</link>
      <description>Traditional sensing techniques apply computational analysis at the output of the sensor hardware to separate signal from noise. A new, more holistic and potentially more powerful approach proposed in this Perspective is designing intelligent sensor systems that ‘lock-in’ to optimal sensing of data, making use of machine leaning strategies.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustoelectronic nanotweezers enable dynamic and large-scale control of nanomaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-24101-z</link>
      <description>Precise and dynamic manipulation of nano-objects on a large scale has been challenging. Here, the authors introduce acoustoelectronic nanotweezers, combining precision of electronic tweezers with large-field dynamic control of acoustic tweezers, demonstrating complex patterning of sub-100 nm objects.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multifunctional wide-angle optics and lasing based on supercell metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-24071-2</link>
      <description>The angular dependence is a well-known issue in metasurface engineering. Here the authors introduce a supercell metasurface able to implement multiple independent functions under large deflection angles with high efficiency, leading to a wavelength tunable laser with arbitrary wavefront control.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication and characterization of resistive double square loop arrays for ultra-wide bandwidth microwave absorption</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-91868-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological gaps by twisting</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-021-00630-3</link>
      <description>All aperiodic systems display an intrinsic degree of freedom, called the phason, and here it is shown that the phason space for twisted bilayered systems is a 2-torus. As a consequence, these systems host the physics of 4-dimensional integer quantum Hall effect, which can be accessed by simply sliding the layers relative to each other.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoscopic and multiscale modelling in materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-020-00913-0</link>
      <description>Multiscale modelling is a powerful tool to simulate materials behaviour, which has important features across multiple length and time scales. This Review provides an overview of multiscale computation methods and discusses their development for use in material design.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active cloaking and illusion of electric potentials in electrostatics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-89062-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibration mitigation of an MDoF system subjected to stochastic loading by means of hysteretic nonlinear locally resonant metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-88984-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanophotonics for light detection and ranging technology</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41565-021-00895-3</link>
      <description>This Review highlights the technological challenges linked to the application of nanophotonics for light detection and ranging (LiDAR).</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological vortices for sound and light</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41565-021-00853-z</link>
      <description>Localized zero-energy fermionic states can bind to topological defects such as two-dimensional vortices, which can be realized in the bulk of artificial acoustic and optical lattices.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable characteristics of low-frequency bandgaps in two-dimensional multivibrator phononic crystal plates under prestrain</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-87904-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silica optical fiber integrated with two-dimensional materials: towards opto-electro-mechanical technology</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-021-00520-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near and mid-infrared optical vortex parametric oscillator based on KTA</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-86945-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phononic metastructures with ultrawide low frequency three-dimensional bandgaps as broadband low frequency filter</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-86520-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforming heat transfer with thermal metamaterials and devices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-021-00283-2</link>
      <description>Artificial structures with novel thermal properties are promising for heat-transfer applications. This Review provides an overview of thermal metamaterials and devices, discussing the working principles underlying the manipulation of thermal conduction and radiation at different length scales.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial assisted illumination nanoscopy via random super-resolution speckles</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-21835-8</link>
      <description>Structured illumination microscopy is usually limited to 2 times spatial resolution improvement over the diffraction limit. Here, the authors introduce a metamaterial structure to generate speckle-like sub-diffraction limit illumination patterns in the near field, and achieve a 7-fold resolution improvement down to 40 nm.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computation and data driven discovery of topological phononic materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-21293-2</link>
      <description>Topological phononic (TP) materials are attracting wide attentions and it is more difficult to seek TP materials compared to electronic materials. Here, the authors present a high-throughput screening and data-driven approach to discover 5014 TP materials and further clarify the mechanism for the occurrence of various TPs.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moulding hydrodynamic 2D-crystals upon parametric Faraday waves in shear-functionalized water surfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-21403-0</link>
      <description>There is a renewed interest in Faraday waves patterns in the field of nonlinear metamaterials due to their tunable templating capacity. Kharbedia et al. show that free-standing water surfaces with ordered patterns can be generated and controlled by the Faraday waves with help of stiffening surfactants.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamical visualization of anisotropic electromagnetic re-emissions from a single metal micro-helix at THz frequencies</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-80510-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic scale displacements detected by optical image cross-correlation analysis and 3D printed marker arrays</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-81712-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong geometry dependence of the Casimir force between interpenetrated rectangular gratings</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-20891-4</link>
      <description>The geometry dependence of the Casimir force could enable applications in nanomechanical systems if the effects can be enhanced. Here, the authors demonstrate that the Casimir force between two interpenetrating nanoscale gratings can exceed the proximity force approximation by a factor of 500.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical memory written and read remotely</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-00080-5</link>
      <description>A device has been developed that consists of mechanical bits, analogous to the magnetic bits used in computer hard drives. Information encoded in the bits programs the mechanical properties of the device.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A structural polymer for highly efficient all-day passive radiative cooling</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-20646-7</link>
      <description>There still remains a big challenge in fabricating highly efficient and low-cost radiative coolers for all-day and all-climates. Here, the authors report a hierarchically structured polymethyl methacrylate film with a micropore array combined with random nanopores for highly efficient day- and nighttime passive radiative cooling.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural multi-colour invisible inks with submicron 4D printing of shape memory polymers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-20300-2</link>
      <description>Four-dimensional (4D) printing of shape memory polymer (SMP) imparts time responsive properties to 3D structures. Here, the authors explore 4D printing of a SMP in the submicron length scale, extending its applications to nanophononics.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harmonic information transitions of spatiotemporal metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-020-00441-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonreciprocal elasticity and the realization of static and dynamic nonreciprocity</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-77949-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineered disorder in photonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-020-00263-y</link>
      <description>In photonics, the introduction of order and disorder has traditionally been treated separately. However, recent developments in nanofabrication and design strategies have enabled the use of materials that lie between the extremes of order and disorder that can yield innovative optical phenomena. This Review surveys the basics and recent achievements of engineered disorder in photonics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the dynamics of hourglass shaped lattice metastructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-77226-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harvesting energy from sun, outer space, and soil</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-77900-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-wavelength lateral detection of tissue-approximating masses using an ultrasonic metamaterial lens</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-19591-2</link>
      <description>Traditional methods for ultrasound detection in biomedical application suffer from limited lateral resolution. Here, the authors show that a phononic metamaterial lens can be used for spatial characterisation of subwavelength objects, even beyond the Fresnel zone of the emitting transducer.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain engineering of 2D semiconductors and graphene: from strain fields to band-structure tuning and photonic applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-020-00421-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D rainbow phononic crystals for extended vibration attenuation bands</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-75977-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A micromirror array with annular partitioning for high-speed random-access axial focusing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-020-00420-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SeMSA: a compact super absorber optimised for broadband, low-frequency noise attenuation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-73933-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-dispersive infrared multi-gas sensing via nanoantenna integrated narrowband detectors</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-19085-1</link>
      <description>Gas sensing based on infrared absorption typically uses narrowband filters paired with detectors to select different gases. Here, the authors propose a multi-gas-sensing platform based on an array of narrowband detectors employing nanoantenna based plasmonic metamaterial absorbers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Casimir forces exerted by epsilon-near-zero hyperbolic materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-73995-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A design strategy to match the band gap of periodic and aperiodic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-73299-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study in circular auxetic structures for efficiency enhancement in piezoelectric vibration energy harvesting</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-73425-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light–matter interactions with photonic quasiparticles</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42254-020-0224-2</link>
      <description>The coupling of photons to material quasiparticles such as plasmons, phonons and excitons opens new possibilities in light–matter interactions. This Review presents a generalized view of such quasiparticles and the technique that describes their interactions with matter: macroscopic quantum electrodynamics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amplification of enantiomeric excess by dynamic inversion of enantiomers in deracemization of Au38 clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-18357-0</link>
      <description>Symmetry breaking and amplification processes play a fundamental role in nature and technology. Here, the authors show that the interplay between racemization and ligand exchange leads to amplification of enantiomeric excess of intrinsically chiral metal clusters.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Luneburg lens for broadband cloaking and wave guiding</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-71124-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-color terahertz spatial light modulator for single-pixel imaging</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-022-00879-5</link>
      <description>Liquid crystal metasurface based spatial light modulator is developed for terahertz dual-color compressive imaging. Significant improvement of imaging quality and speed is demonstrated using proposed auto-calibrated algorithms and frequency-switching method.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy harvesting from sonic noises by phononic crystal fibers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-14134-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly tunable low frequency metamaterial cavity for vibration localization</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-13453-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-sensitive polarization-resolved black phosphorus homojunction photodetector defined by ferroelectric domains</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-30951-y</link>
      <description>Integrated polarization-sensitive photodetectors are important for sensing applications and optical communication. Here, the authors report the realization of 2D black phosphorus homojunction photodetectors defined by ferroelectric substrates, showing polarization ratios up to 288 and high responsivity in the near-infrared.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A portable non-invasive microwave based head imaging system using compact metamaterial loaded 3D unidirectional antenna for stroke detection</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-12860-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface acoustic wave coupling between micromechanical resonators</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-022-00895-2</link>
      <description>As the size of mechanical resonators is decreased, their resonance frequencies increase and acoustic wave-like propagation in their substrate becomes important. Here, the coupling of two micromechanical resonators by surface acoustic waves is modelled analytically and numerically, showing dispersive and dissipative coupling of the resonators.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gap coupled symmetric split ring resonator based near zero index ENG metamaterial for gain improvement of monopole antenna</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-11029-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A crystal of light vortices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-022-00996-y</link>
      <description>Researchers report a solid-state laser containing metasurfaces that generates a 10 × 10 array of phase-locked optical vortices with tunable orbital angular momentum.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material-specific high-resolution table-top extreme ultraviolet microscopy</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-022-00797-6</link>
      <description>The combination of a state-of-the-art high harmonic source, structured EUV light, and advanced ptychography reconstruction algorithms enables material-specific high-contrast and high-resolution imaging on the nanoscale.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of polarization modulator using MXene thin film</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-10768-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic metasurface for programming electromagnetic beam scanning on the Azimuth and elevation planes</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-022-00371-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piezoelectric energy harvesting using mechanical metamaterials and phononic crystals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-022-00869-4</link>
      <description>Judicious design of metamaterials and phononic crystals permits the realization of novel localization and wave-guiding properties. Here, recent developments and strategies for applying these structures to piezoelectric energy harvesting are reviewed.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale hierarchical structures from a nanocluster mesophase</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-022-01223-3</link>
      <description>Nanometre-sized clusters can self-organize into centimetre-scale hierarchical structures, mimicking the complex constructions seen in nature and providing a platform to design synthetically directed advanced materials with sophisticated functions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual estimation of the force applied by another person</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-10243-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A metafluid with multistable density and internal energy states</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-29048-3</link>
      <description>Investigating and tailoring the thermodynamic properties of different fluids is crucial to many applied fields such as energy and refrigeration cycles. Here, authors use multistable, gas filled, particles suspension to enhance the macro-properties of thermodynamic fluids.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and optimization of three-dimensional composite multilayer cylindrical pentamode metamaterials for controlling low frequency acoustic waves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-09313-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the performances of the vibrating barriers for the seismic protection of the Zoser pyramid</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-09444-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold photo-carving of halogen-bonded co-crystals of a dye and a volatile co-former using visible light</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41557-022-00909-0</link>
      <description>Halogen-bonded co-crystals of a fluorinated azobenzene derivative and a volatile co-former can be cut, carved or engraved with micrometre-scale precision using low-power visible light. The proposed mechanism involves the local evaporation of the volatile component followed by recrystallization of the azobenzene co-former near the edge of the irradiation area.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral carbon dots: synthesis, optical properties, and emerging applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-022-00764-1</link>
      <description>This review focuses on chiral carbon dots, introducing their chemical syntheses, morphology and optical/chiroptical properties, and considering their emerging applications in sensing, bioimaging and catalysis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realization of ultrathin waveguides by elastic metagratings</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-022-00843-0</link>
      <description>Guidance of classical waves is key to many technologies, but high-efficiency, omnidirectional performance is difficult to achieve. Here, an ultrathin, broadband elastic metagrating is proposed for suppression of parasitic diffraction and guiding waves along an arbitrary path.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soft wearable devices for deep-tissue sensing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-022-00427-y</link>
      <description>Wearable devices can sense physiological signals on the surface of the human body. This Review discusses the design, sensing mechanisms and fabrication of wearable devices that can probe deep-tissue signals, beyond the skin, to provide information about human health and disease.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extremely low frequency wave localization via elastic foundation induced metamaterial with a spiral cavity</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-08002-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbolic shear polaritons in low-symmetry crystals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-04328-y</link>
      <description>Shear phenomena in the infrared dielectric response of a monoclinic crystal are shown to unveil a new polariton class termed hyperbolic shear polariton that can emerge in any low-symmetry monoclinic or triclinic system.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planar ultrasonic transducer based on a metasurface piezoelectric ring array for subwavelength acoustic focusing in water</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-05547-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain and pseudo-magnetic fields in optical lattices from density-assisted tunneling</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-022-00802-9</link>
      <description>Realizing and controlling artificial gauge fields in quantum systems constitutes an intriguing route towards simulating of exotic quantum theories. Here, the authors propose a tunable strategy to engineer strain and synthetic magnetic fields in optical lattices from coupling to trapped Bose-Einstein condensates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Octet lattice-based plate for elastic wave control</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-04900-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum photonics with layered 2D materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42254-021-00408-0</link>
      <description>Quantum photonics offers an integrated and scalable approach to quantum information processing and communication. This article summarizes the state of the art and provides an outlook on future challenges and opportunities for quantum photonics based on 2D materials.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust separation of topological in-plane and out-of-plane waves in a phononic crystal</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-021-00793-z</link>
      <description>Judicious design of acoustic metamaterials has so far permitted control of topologically-protected waves in one plane of a two-dimensional system. Here, the symmetry of a phononic crystal is tuned geometrically to realise independent tuning of both in-plane and out-of-plane topological modes in the same frequency range.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanophotonics shines light on hyperbolic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-021-00688-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic capsulate triboelectric nanogenerators</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-04100-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy polymer produces a giant electrocaloric effect at low fields</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-04189-5</link>
      <description>A study reports and characterizes a high-entropy electrocaloric polymer that switches under low fields, and discusses its potential suitability for use in caloric heat pumps.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-enhanced mid-infrared absorption spectroscopy using miniaturized-disc metasurface</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-02984-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optomechanics for quantum technologies</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-021-01402-0</link>
      <description>Interaction with light can be used to precisely control motional states. This Review surveys recent progress in the preparation of non-classical mechanical states and in the application of optomechanical platforms to specific tasks in quantum technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colossal magnetic fields in high refractive index materials at microwave frequencies</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-01644-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light–matter coupling in large-area van der Waals superlattices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41565-021-01023-x</link>
      <description>Square-centimetre scale, multilayer superlattice structures based on atomically thin two-dimensional chalcogenide monolayers enable the realization of excitonic metamaterials.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of elastic spin with chiral meta-sources</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-27254-z</link>
      <description>’Following up on the recent theoretical demonstration here the authors bring us a step closer to the real implementation of efficient ultrasonic chiral sources. They experimentally demonstrate the presence of elastic spin waves, Rayleigh and Lamb waves, generated by a chiral-meta source, characterizing their basic properties.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A highly stable, nanotube-enhanced, CMOS-MEMS thermal emitter for mid-IR gas sensing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-02121-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optical meta-waveguides for integrated photonics and beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-021-00655-x</link>
      <description>Recent years have witnessed substantial potential in allying meta-optics with diverse waveguide platforms to enable exotic manipulation of guided light signals. This review cataloged recent advances on meta-waveguides for photonic integration.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetoactive acoustic metamaterials based on nanoparticle-enhanced diaphragm</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-01569-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a self tuning sliding mass metastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-00526-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireless power transfer based on novel physical concepts</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-021-00658-x</link>
      <description>This Review examines the development of novel physical effects and materials for wireless power transfer, considering techniques based on coherent perfect absorption, parity–time symmetry and exceptional points, and on-site power generation, as well as the use of metamaterials and metasurfaces, and acoustic power transfer.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of clay soil/CuFe2O4 nanocomposite toward improving energy and shielding efficiency of buildings</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-00347-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct electrical modulation of second-order optical susceptibility via phase transitions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-021-00655-0</link>
      <description>Electrically induced transitions between hexagonal and monoclinic phases of molybdenum ditelluride can be used to make a second-harmonic-generation modulator with an on/off ratio of 1,000 and a broad bandwidth.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical computing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03623-y</link>
      <description>Computing approaches based on mechanical mechanisms are discussed, with a view towards a framework in which adaptable materials and structures act as a distributed information processing network.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of relative density on quasi-static and fatigue failure of lattice structures in Ti6Al4V produced by laser powder bed fusion</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-98631-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards altering sound frequency at will by a linear meta-layer with time-varying and quantized properties</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-021-00721-1</link>
      <description>Temporal modulation materials have been attracting attention thanks to their ability to break wave reciprocity, i.e., waves traveling from point A to B are identical to waves propagating from B to A. The authors present a linear temporal modulation device with a giant acoustic impedance modulation ratio and ability to linearly change wave frequency, operating in two quantized states when a shunt circuit is connected and disconnected by a MOSFET.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase control of terahertz waves moves on chip</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-021-00887-8</link>
      <description>The phase of terahertz waves can now be precisely modulated electronically using a chip-based digitally coded phase shifter. The achievement is a step towards chip-scale integrated terahertz technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead-substituted barium hexaferrite for tunable terahertz optoelectronics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41427-021-00331-x</link>
      <description>Multiferroic lead-doped barium hexaferrite exhibits remarkably rich set of phenomena at frequencies from Hertz to near infrared, including tunable terahertz resonance. Unveiling microscopic mechanisms responsible for such extraordinary response paves the way for controllable tuning of the functional characteristics of the material demanded by next-generation terahertz electronics.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biochar as a low-cost, eco-friendly, and electrically conductive material for terahertz applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-98009-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum-field-induced THz transport gap in a carbon nanotube quantum dot</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-25733-x</link>
      <description>Strong light-matter coupling has been realized at the level of single atoms and photons throughout most of the electromagnetic spectrum, except for the THz range. Here, the authors report a THz-scale transport gap, induced by vacuum fluctuations in carbon nanotube quantum dot through the deep strong coupling of a single electron to a THz resonator.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-orientable order and non-commutative response in frustrated metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06022-7</link>
      <description>We describe globally frustrated matter as deformations of non-orientable surfaces, with the concept of non-orientable order we demonstrate topologically protected mechanical memories, suggesting a design principle for effectively storing information in frustrated metamaterials.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of acoustic absorbing metasurfaces using a data-driven approach</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-023-00369-0</link>
      <description>Designing artificial acoustic metasurfaces via traditional numerical simulations is computationally challenging. Here, the authors introduce a data-driven neural network approach for the inverse design of membrane-type sound absorbers, testing the desired properties on two devices fabricated using model-estimated parameters.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-resolution scalable microprinting</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-023-00537-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development, fabrication and mechanical characterisation of auxetic bicycle handlebar grip</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-35418-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrabroadband sound control with deep-subwavelength plasmacoustic metalayers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-38522-5</link>
      <description>Controlling audible sound requires inherently broadband and subwavelength acoustic solutions. Exploiting the unique physics of plasmacoustic metalayers, we experimentally demonstrate versatile and tunable sound control over a wide frequency range.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin acoustic metamaterial as super absorber for broadband low-frequency underwater sound</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-34993-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-plane hyperbolic polariton tuners in terahertz and long-wave infrared regimes</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-38214-0</link>
      <description>In-plane hyperbolic phonon polaritons in α-MoO3 crystals hold promise for terahertz (THz) and longwave infrared (LWIR) photonic applications, but their coupling with far-field excitations remains challenging. Here, the authors report the fabrication of α-MoO3 ribbon arrays that can be applied as tunable THz and LWIR filters and polarizers.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picophotonic localization metrology beyond thermal fluctuations</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-023-01543-y</link>
      <description>The authors report subatomic precision in measuring the displacement of a nanowire. Such precision is achieved by employing deep-learning enabled analysis of single-shot scattering of topologically structured superoscillatory illumination.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encoding reprogrammable properties into magneto-mechanical materials via topology optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41524-023-00980-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unusual nonlinear switching in branched carbon nanotube nanocomposites</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-32331-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial can help buildings withstand earthquakes</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d44151-023-00033-z</link>
      <description>It lessens the intensity of seismic waves and blocks their propagation through building frames</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbolic whispering-gallery phonon polaritons in boron nitride nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41565-023-01324-3</link>
      <description>A Purcell factor as high as 1012 is measured in atomically smooth nanocavities of hexagonal boron nitride nanotubes.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light People: Prof. Sir John Pendry, father of metamaterials, spoke about the future of meta</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-023-01082-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Rabi dynamics of trapped atoms far in the deep strong coupling regime</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-36611-z</link>
      <description>Light interaction with atoms depends on the strength of the light-matter coupling and the energy splitting of the modes involved. Here the authors study of quantum Rabi dynamics in a deep strong coupling regime by using a cloud of cold rubidium atoms.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photonic comb-rooted synthesis of ultra-stable terahertz frequencies</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-36507-y</link>
      <description>The authors present a photonic scheme for terahertz synthesis using an optical frequency comb in stabilization to an ultra-low expansion optical cavity, achieving an unprecedented level of frequency instability of 10−15 at 1-s integration over the tunable range of 0.1–1.1 THz.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape-memory effect in twisted ferroic nanocomposites</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-36274-w</link>
      <description>Shape-memory materials are promising actuation sources for small-scale machines. The authors demonstrate that domain switching in twisted ferroic nanocomposites enables a giant shape-memory effect and superelasticity in the nanoscale structure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial foundation for seismic wave attenuation for low and wide frequency band</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27678-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear Rayleigh wave propagation in a layered half-space in dual-phase-lag</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-29411-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gigahertz optoacoustic vibration in Sub-5 nm tip-supported nano-optomechanical metasurface</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-36127-6</link>
      <description>Nano-optomechanical systems plays an indispensable role in all-optical manipulation of light but high energy losses severely limit their development. Here the authors show ultrafast all-optical manipulation in a sub-5 nm tip-supported optomechanical metasurface.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocrystal phononics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-022-01438-4</link>
      <description>Colloidal nanocrystals can form into periodic superlattices exhibiting collective vibrations from the correlated motion of the nanocrystals. This Perspective discusses such collective vibrations and their as-of-yet untapped potential applications for phononic crystals, acoustic metamaterials and optomechanical systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoscale molecular rectifiers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41570-022-00457-8</link>
      <description>Molecular rectifiers are an essential component for the construction of molecular electronic devices, which are becoming potentially competitive with existing silicon-based devices. This Review provides an overview of molecular rectification and discusses the outlook for the field as well as prospects for commercialization.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realizing acoustic qubit analogues with nonlinearly tunable phi-bits in externally driven coupled acoustic waveguides</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27427-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-vectoring electromagnetic soft robots with high operational dimensionality</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-35848-y</link>
      <description>Achieving efficiently reprogrammable actuation and high operational dimensionality for soft robots with a limited number of actuators are challenging. Here, Li et al. use the vector control to manipulate electromagnetic soft robots enabling reprogrammable shape morphing and multimodal locomotion.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective medium theory for the low-temperature heat capacity of a metasolid plate</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-022-00329-0</link>
      <description>Modeling artificial nanostructures in terms of effective materials parameters is important for gaining physical insight into their behavior and facilitating their optimization. Here, an analytical effective medium theory for the heat capacity of holey phononic crystals is derived, revealing the effect of the emergent anisotropic elastic response of the metasolid.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Negative Poisson’s ratio polyethylene matrix and 0.5Ba(Zr0.2 Ti0.8) O3–0.5(Ba0.7 Ca0.3)TiO3 based piezocomposite for sensing and energy harvesting applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-26834-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconfigurable metasurfaces towards commercial success</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-022-01099-4</link>
      <description>Recent developments in reconfigurable metasurfaces are reviewed with a focus on case studies that are promising for commercialization and associated challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-shot 3D imaging with point cloud projection based on metadevice</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-35483-z</link>
      <description>The authors present a single-shot 3D imaging approach utilizing carefully designed point clouds projection based on a metasurface device. They show submillimeter depth accuracy and demonstrate the potential for hand gesture detection.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enantioselective sensing by collective circular dichroism</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-05353-1</link>
      <description>An array of 2D crystals of isotropic, 432-symmetric chiral gold nanoparticles is shown to exhibit collective resonances with a strong and uniform chiral near field, allowing enantioselective detection by the collective circular dichroism.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Road to entire insulation for resonances from a forced mechanical system</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-25691-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soft metamaterial with programmable ferromagnetism</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-022-00463-2</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miniaturized electromechanical devices with multi-vibration modes achieved by orderly stacked structure with piezoelectric strain units</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-34231-7</link>
      <description>Most piezoelectric coefficients in piezoelectric ceramics are zero, resulting in many piezoelectric vibration modes cannot be excited. Here, the authors propose an orderly stacked structure to achieve all nonzero piezoelectric coefficients.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quantum graph approach to metamaterial design</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-22265-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A multifunctional ultra-thin acoustic membrane with self-healing properties for adaptive low-frequency noise control</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-22441-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Hermitian elastodynamics in gyro-odd continuum media</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-022-00297-5</link>
      <description>Active metamaterials can host non-Hermitian interactions that defy the conservation laws of linear elasticity, leading to unusual phenomena such as one-way energy transmission and odd-elastic moduli. Here, robust unidirectional Rayleigh surface waves are found in active media comprising both gyroscopic and odd-elastic effects.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonvolatile chirality switching in terahertz chalcogenide metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-022-00445-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giant mid-IR resonant coupling to molecular vibrations in sub-nm gaps of plasmonic multilayer metafilms</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-022-00943-0</link>
      <description>Short-range ordered plasmonic superlattices of Au nanoparticles have tunable infrared collective plasmon-polariton resonances. The enhanced molecule-plasmon interaction approaches the vibrational strong coupling regime, enabling molecular sensing through giant infrared absorption.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological state transfer in Kresling origami</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-022-00280-0</link>
      <description>Topological mechanical metamaterials have been considered effective for energy manipulation via edge states, but manipulating these states remains challenging. Here, a Kresling origami mechanical metamaterial hosts multiple topological edge states at finite frequencies, which can be manipulated and transferred across the boundaries of the system by adjusting the lattice torsion.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in acoustofluidic separation technology in biology</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-022-00435-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphite-oxide hybrid multi-degree of freedom resonator metamaterial for broadband sound absorption</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-14415-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological acoustics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-022-00465-6</link>
      <description>The introduction of topology into acoustic platforms enables robust sound control. This Review discusses the fundamental mechanisms, basic designs, practical realizations and promising future directions for topological acoustic systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstration of a two-bit controlled-NOT quantum-like gate using classical acoustic qubit-analogues</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18314-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireless power transfer system for deep-implanted biomedical devices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18000-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral trabeated metabeam for low-frequency multimode wave mitigation via dual-bandgap mechanism</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-022-00974-4</link>
      <description>Engineering the mechanical response of metamaterials allows control of mechanical modes, with potential application to vibrational isolation. Here, a general framework for achieving a complete band-gap by combining orthogonal flexural and longitudinal-torsional band-gaps is demonstrated analytically and experimentally.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo-responsive hydrogel-based re-programmable metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-15453-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging physical intelligence for the self-design of high performance engineering structures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-15229-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in microsystem approaches for mechanical characterization of soft biological tissues</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-022-00412-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple sacrificial-layer-free microfabrication processes for air-cavity Fresnel acoustic lenses (ACFALs) with improved focusing performance</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-022-00407-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hypocrystalline ceramic aerogels for thermal insulation at extreme conditions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04784-0</link>
      <description>Hypocrystalline ceramic aerogels with a zig-zag architecture show high thermal stability under thermal shock and exposure to high temperature, providing a reliable material system for thermal insulation at extreme conditions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface plasmons induce topological transition in graphene/α-MoO3 heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-31477-z</link>
      <description>Hyperbolic phonon polaritons – mixed states of photons and anisotropic lattice vibrations – offer appealing properties for nanophotonic applications. Here, the authors show that the plasmon-phonon hybridization upon electronic doping in graphene/α-MoO3 heterostructures can induce topological transitions of the polariton wavefront.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electromagnetic energy density in hyperbolic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-14909-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial-based passive analog processor for wireless vibration sensing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44172-024-00190-8</link>
      <description>Real-time, low-cost, and wireless mechanical vibration monitoring is necessary for industrial, environmental, and biomedical applications. Here, Dajun Zhang and colleagues report a passive,ss metamaterial-based device which substantially improves the sensitivity of wireless vibration measurement methods when attached to vibrating surfaces.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vision-driven metasurfaces for perception enhancement</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45296-x</link>
      <description>Authors showcase a framework for visual perception enhancement system based on vision-driven metasurfaces. It can help humans obtain information in multiple frequency bands and allows the metasurface platform with more interesting functions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giant electric field-induced second harmonic generation in polar skyrmions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45755-5</link>
      <description>Electric modulation of second harmonic generation finds applications in integrated photonics. Here, authors introduce electric field-induced second harmonic generation by polar skyrmions in PbTiO3/SrTiO3 superlattices with giant modulation depth.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusive kinks turn kirigami into machines</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45602-7</link>
      <description>Kinks define boundaries between distinct configurations of a material. Here, the authors reveal the emergence of propagating kinks in purely dissipative kirigami and show that such structures can shape-change into different textures depending on how fast they are stretched enabling basic mechanical tasks.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable conversion of alkaline nitrate to ammonia at activities greater than 2 A cm−2</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45534-2</link>
      <description>Alkaline nitrate electroreduction to ammonia is restricted by insufficient H+ supply. Here, the authors propose a halogen-mediated H+ feeding strategy, by triggering dangling O-H water dissociation and fast *H desorption for *NO intermediate hydrogenation, to enhance the formation of ammonia.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin resolved topological bulk state in acoustics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53226-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bilateral passive thermal management for dynamical temperature regulation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53433-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibrations and energy distribution in inhomogeneous rods with elastic and viscous boundary conditions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52860-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing transparent piezoelectric metasurfaces for adaptive optics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45088-3</link>
      <description>Most multi-degrees-of-freedom systems are composed of several piezoelectric stacks, leading to cumbersome and complicated structures. Here, the authors propose a piezo metasurface to achieve various types of high strains in a wide frequency range.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roadmapping the next generation of silicon photonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-44750-0</link>
      <description>In order to complete the transition to the era of large-scale integration, silicon photonics will have to overcome several challenges. Here, the authors outline what these challenges are and what it will take to tackle them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling the motion of gravitational spinners and waves in chiral waveguides</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-50052-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct laser-written optomechanical membranes in fiber Fabry-Perot cavities</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-44490-7</link>
      <description>Authors showcase 3D direct laser writing to fabricate optically interfaced mechanical resonators. The membrane-type structures are placed inside fiber Fabry-Perot cavities to realize a miniaturized optical cavity. Further, the optomechanical properties reveal the coupling mechanism and a significant tuning of the mechanical resonator frequency.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planar hyperbolic polaritons in 2D van der Waals materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-43992-8</link>
      <description>In this Perspective, the authors illustrate the physics of hyperbolic polaritons in anisotropic 2D and 1D materials, proposing new potential material candidates, forward looking opportunities and technological applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Folk arts-inspired twice-coagulated configuration-editable tough aerogels enabled by transformable gel precursors</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-44156-4</link>
      <description>Aerogels attract considerable attention in various emerging fields in recent decades, but low density and weak mechanical performance make their configuration-editing capability challenging. Here the authors establish an efficient twice-coagulated strategy to fabricate configuration-editable tough aerogels enabled by transformable gel precursors.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking symmetry creates polar auxeticity</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-023-01750-7</link>
      <description>By forming a heterostructure interface, and by judicious choice of crystallographic orientation, piezoelectrics are developed that show expansion or contraction along all axes on application of an electric field.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme light confinement and control in low-symmetry phonon-polaritonic crystals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-023-00620-7</link>
      <description>Broken symmetries at the nanoscale can greatly modify the emergent nanophotonic responses enabled by phonon polaritons. This Review discusses how lowering the degree of symmetry in natural and artificial materials gives rise to a wide spectrum of low-loss, directional, confined light–matter quasiparticles.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverse design of nonlinear mechanical metamaterials via video denoising diffusion models</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-023-00762-x</link>
      <description>Machine learning models have been widely used in the inverse design of new materials, but typically only linear properties could be targeted. Bastek and Kochmann show that video diffusion generative models can produce the nonlinear deformation and stress response of cellular materials under large-scale compression.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement learning optimisation for graded metamaterial design using a physical-based constraint on the state representation and action space</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-48927-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High specificity THz metamaterial-based biosensor for label-free transcription factor detection in melanoma diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-46876-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakdown of conventional winding number calculation in one-dimensional lattices with interactions beyond nearest neighbors</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-023-01461-0</link>
      <description>Topological insulators are bulk insulators with conducting zero-energy edge states conventionally predicted by topological indices, such as winding numbers in one-dimensional lattices. Here, the authors use the Jackiw-Rebbi theory to reveal that the number of topologically protected zero-energy states can be higher than the winding number.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser-induced vibrations probe microscale metamaterials without contacting them</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-03159-3</link>
      <description>Advanced materials engineered at the microscale have the potential to achieve unparalleled mechanical performance under extreme conditions. A laser-based characterization method enables the fast measurement of extreme properties in these materials, by extracting them from the sample’s vibrational ‘fingerprint’, without touching or permanently deforming the structure.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic diagnosis of metamaterials through laser-induced vibrational signatures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06652-x</link>
      <description>A high-throughput, non-contact framework is described that uses the laser-induced vibrational signatures of metamaterials to non-destructively quantify their omnidirectional elastic information, dynamic linear properties, damping properties and defects.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-noise fluorescent detection of cardiac troponin I in human serum based on surface acoustic wave separation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-023-00600-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple impact effects of helium-driven shocks on thin fiber-metal laminates</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-42861-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualization analysis of research hotspots on structural topology optimization based on CiteSpace</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-45447-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A reprogrammable mechanical metamaterial with origami functional-group transformation and ring reconfiguration</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-42323-1</link>
      <description>Programmability is a key property for multifunctional metamaterials, but it is limited by homo-element. Here, the authors show a mechanical metamaterials with heterogeneous elements, achieving various mechanical behaviours by functional group transformation and ring configuration.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential terahertz therapeutic strategy for the prevention or mitigation of Alzheimer’s disease pathology</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-023-01289-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic metamaterials based on polymer sheets: from material design to applications as sound insulators and vibration dampers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41428-023-00842-0</link>
      <description>For uniform and flat materials, heavier plates show higher sound insulation performance because of the mass law. Acoustic metamaterials with periodic resonance structures have attracted attention as ultra-lightweight sound insulators that can break the mass law limit. Recently, practical acoustic metamaterial sheets that allow high-throughput fabrication and single-step implementation on target objects have been developed based on polymer materials. In this Focus Review, the polymer-based material design, the control of acoustic functions based on polymer properties, and applications as sound insulators and vibration dampers are described.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical metamaterials and beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-41679-8</link>
      <description>Mechanical metamaterials are known for their unconventional mechanical properties. In this perspective, the authors give an overview of the current state of mechanical materials research and suggest a roadmap for next-generation active and responsive mechanical metamaterials.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damping contribution of viscoelastic core on airborne sound insulation performance of finite constrained layer damping panels at low and middle frequencies</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-42391-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active acoustic field modulation of ultrasonic transducers with flexible composites</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-023-01361-3</link>
      <description>The development of technologies to manipulate acoustic waves relies on acoustic lenses and ultrasonic arrays, but it is limited by low transmission efficiencies or bulky setups. The authors propose a flexible and efficient piezoelectric ultrasonic transducer that generates intricate ultrasound wave patterns and deviate from conventional approaches.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly sensitive and broadband meta-mechanoreceptor via mechanical frequency-division multiplexing</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-41222-9</link>
      <description>There’s a trade-off between the sensitivity and bandwidth for mechanics guided sensor designs. Here, authors report a mechanical sensor comprised of piezoelectric resonators with near infinite effective piezoelectric coefficients, leading to highly sensitive and broadband micromotion sensing.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibrational circular dichroism unveils hidden clues</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-023-01239-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D-printed PEDOT:PSS for soft robotics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-023-00587-5</link>
      <description>Combining poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene):polystyrene sulfonate (PEDOT:PSS) with 3D-printing techniques enables the customization of compliant conductive materials for soft robotics, towards the goal of merging humans and robots. This Review discusses the fundamentals of 3D-printed PEDOT:PSS for soft robotics, from printable ink design and evaluation to printing strategies and promising soft robotic systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial dielectric beam-scanning prism for the terahertz region</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-41046-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dexterous electrical-driven soft robots with reconfigurable chiral-lattice foot design</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-40626-x</link>
      <description>Animals use dexterous locomotion to hunt for food or flee from danger. Inspired by this strategy, Wang et al. design a soft robot, containing dielectric elastomer artificial muscles and reconfigurable chiral feet, which enables spontaneous change in movement direction in a controlled and reversible way.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable optical topological transitions of plasmon polaritons in WTe2 van der Waals films</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-023-01244-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-reciprocal and non-Newtonian mechanical metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-40493-6</link>
      <description>In this work, authors demonstrate a model for non-reciprocal and non-Newtonian mechanical metamaterials by combining the concept of local resonances and fixing boundaries. Via computational models and impact experiments they show that stiffness substantially changes as a function of the loading velocity.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model-predicted geometry variations to compensate material variability in the design of classical guitars</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-37943-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terahertz sensing of reduced graphene oxide nanosheets using sub-wavelength dipole cavities</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-39498-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological solitonic macromolecules</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-40335-5</link>
      <description>The formation of soliton macromolecules or metamaterial analogues of polymers with inter-soliton binding resembling strong covalent-like chemical bonds has not been considered so far. Zhao et al. experimentally create and theoretically, model soliton macromolecules, called “polyskyrmionomers”, introducing polymer-mimicking designs of topological chiral meta matter that promise technological utility in data storage and electro-optics.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active self-assembly of piezoelectric biomolecular films via synergistic nanoconfinement and in-situ poling</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-39692-y</link>
      <description>Piezoelectric biomaterials are limited by the challenges in domain orientation alignment and a weak piezoelectric effect. Here, Zhang et. al. present an active self-assembly strategy via nanoconfinement and in-situ poling, to obtain large-scale, high performance piezoelectric β-glycine nanocrystalline films.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing adaptive bistable stiffness of hair-cell-bundle structure for broadband vibration applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-37962-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anomalous fractal scaling in two-dimensional electric networks</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-023-01266-1</link>
      <description>Scaling theory governs much of the physics around us. Here, the authors present experimental evidence showcasing the breakdown of logarithmic scaling in electric circuits and the emergence of fractal-like patterns in impedance scaling relationships.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding chiral metamaterials for retrieving fingerprints via vibrational circular dichroism</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-023-01186-3</link>
      <description>We demonstrate surface-enhanced vibrational circular dichroism spectroscopy for chiral mixture detection, enabled by MIR chiral metamaterial platform.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A second wave of topological phenomena in photonics and acoustics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06163-9</link>
      <description>The current state of the art of topological phenomena in photonics and acoustics is reviewed and future research directions for valuable applications are discussed.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated metasurfaces for re-envisioning a near-future disruptive optical platform</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-023-01169-4</link>
      <description>We organize integrated metasurfaces with conventional devices (LED, LC, MEMS, etc.), and their potential applications in VR/AR, LiDAR, and sensors.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asynchronous locking in metamaterials of fluids of light and sound</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-38788-9</link>
      <description>Exciton-polariton condensates are hybrid systems with nonlinear interactions. Here the authors demonstrate metamaterials with inter-site polariton coupling and asynchronous locking of light fluids from neighbor sites at the energy detuning.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design, fabrication and assembly considerations for electronic systems made of fibre devices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-023-00573-x</link>
      <description>Integrating single-functional fibre devices into multifunctional systems can enable promising wearable applications. This Perspective article summarizes challenges and strategies for the design, fabrication and assembly of fibre electronic systems, highlighting specifications for real applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-thin light-weight laser-induced-graphene (LIG) diffractive optics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-023-01143-0</link>
      <description>We present how direct-laser-writing can be utilized to fabricate ultra-thin light-weight planar diffractive optics with graphene as the base material. (Inset scale bar: 1 mm).</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unprecedented mechanical wave energy absorption observed in multifunctional bioinspired architected metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41427-024-00565-5</link>
      <description>Noise and impact hazards are pervasive in engineering, necessitating materials capable of absorbing both sound and stress wave energy. Here, we present bioinspired metamaterials with exceptional sound-absorbing and mechanical properties using a weakly-coupled design strategy. These materials incorporate multi-layered resonators for superior acoustic performance and cambered cell walls for enhanced structural strength. They achieve an average absorption coefficient of 0.80 across the 1.0 to 6.0 kHz range, all within a sleek 21 mm thickness. Furthermore, the design transitions failure modes from catastrophic to progressive, resulting in a remarkable 558.4% increase in energy absorption compared to conventional designs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-picosecond, strain-tunable, polarization-selective optical switching via anisotropic exciton dynamics in quasi-1D ZrSe3</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-024-01585-0</link>
      <description>Strain control of quasi-1D ZrSe3 enables ultrafast, polarization-selective optical switching with enhanced selectivity and tunable switching energies.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polarization management in silicon photonics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44310-024-00033-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero-power infrared switch with two-phase microfluidic flow and a 2D material thermal isolation layer</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-024-00761-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating topological valley disclinations using multiple scattering and null-field theories</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-024-00618-w</link>
      <description>Topological metamaterials are becoming increasingly interesting for their wave-confining capabilities, providing topologically robust guiding of light, sound and vibrations. Here, topological edge and disclination states in valley Hall sonic lattices are investigated via a non-commercial analytical approach combining the null-field method with multiple scattering techniques.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature tunability of topological phase transitions and edge states in two-dimensional acoustic topological insulators</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-71021-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear static and dynamic response of a metastructure exhibiting quasi-zero-stiffness characteristics for vibration control: an experimental validation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-70126-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning enables the discovery of 2D Invar and anti-Invar monolayers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-51379-6</link>
      <description>Invar materials (characterized by a thermal expansion coefficient close to zero) have potential for thermal management applications, but their number is limited. Here, the authors report machine-learning-assisted high-throughput calculations to identify Invar and anti-Invar monolayers.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ocean wave energy harvesting with high energy density and self-powered monitoring system</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-50926-5</link>
      <description>Point-defect metamaterials have the property of concentrating vibration energy at the defect location. We design an environmental monitoring node based on this property, which can efficiently convert wave kinetic energy into electrical energy for real-time monitoring of the ocean environment.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polaritonic states trapped by topological defects</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-50666-6</link>
      <description>Topological traps and guides for polaritons expand the potential for light-matter wave manipulation in ultrathin materials, facilitating photonic on-chip integration. Here the authors demonstrate a chiral-defect cavity in a planar metasurface that efficiently trap mid-IR phonon-polaritons in topological defects.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconfigurable metamaterial processing units that solve arbitrary linear calculus equations</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-50483-x</link>
      <description>A reconfigurable metamaterial processing unit that solves arbitrary linear calculus equations is proposed. With the merits of compactness, reconfigurability, and reusability, the proposed MPU provides a potential route for high speed computing.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-plane hyperbolic phonon polaritons: materials, properties, and nanophotonic devices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44310-024-00019-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic excitations at the plasmon–molecule interface</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-024-02537-6</link>
      <description>Plasmonic excitations can enhance the interaction between a metal and molecules adsorbed onto its surface. This Review summarizes the different effects involved in this process and places them into a framework based on electron scattering.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadening bandgaps in a multi-resonant piezoelectric metamaterial plate via bandgap merging phenomena</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-66849-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D/2D coupled MOF/Fe composite metamaterials enable robust ultra–broadband microwave absorption</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-49762-4</link>
      <description>Here the Authors showcase a microwave absorber design that combines semiconductive metal-organic frameworks with iron 2D layers, achieving ultra-broadband absorption in the whole 5 G frequencies and stable performance against various angles and polarizations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible two-way tuning of thermal conductivity in an end-linked star-shaped thermoset</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-49354-2</link>
      <description>The need for reversible yet sizable thermal conductivity tuning in bulk materials impedes practical thermal switch design. Here, the authors report a scalable polymer which achieves a reversible 14 × tuning ratio via strain and temperature modulation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An adjustable acoustic metamaterial cell using a magnetic membrane for tunable resonance</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-65819-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging probing perspective of two-dimensional materials physics: terahertz emission spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-024-01486-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of data-driven modeling method for nonlinear coupling components</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-65680-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origami engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43586-024-00313-7</link>
      <description>Origami engineering offers a conceptual framework for non-destructive and scale-independent abstractions for engineering applications. In this Primer, Misseroni et al. provide a comprehensive overview of the major principles and elements in origami engineering, including theoretical fundamentals, simulation tools, manufacturing techniques and testing protocols.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terahertz phonon engineering with van der Waals heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-07604-9</link>
      <description>In an application of terahertz phonon engineering, terahertz phonons were generated, detected and manipulated through precise integration of atomically thin layers in van der Waals heterostructures.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable acoustic vortex generation by a compact rotating disk</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01682-x</link>
      <description>The tunability of acoustic vortices topological charge and working frequency is pivotal for efficient optical angular momentum generation, but its manipulation typically involves bulky setups. Here, the authors use aerodynamic dipole sources from a rotating disk to generate acoustic vortices with different topological charges in a compact setup.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sol–gel derived ceramic nanoparticles as an alternative material for microstrip patch antenna in WLAN applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-63454-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A bioinspired surface tension-driven route toward programmed cellular ceramics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-49345-3</link>
      <description>Three-dimensional architecture engineering allows for higher performance ceramics with more diverse applications. Here, the authors report a simple and efficient manufacturing process for cellular ceramics in programmed cell-based 3D configurations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology-forcing to reduce environmental noise pollution: a prospectus</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41370-024-00679-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel smart hybrid multimorph piezoelectric spherical shell cloak for broadband near-perfect underwater acoustic camouflage applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-63201-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easy-to-actuate multi-compatible truss structures with prescribed reconfiguration</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-49210-3</link>
      <description>Multi-stable structures are useful in soft robotics with fewer and lightweight actuators for rapid motion. Here, authors propose a full cycle design framework for morphing structures including multi-stability, stiffness design, minimum energy-path finding, and pulling actuation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Injectable ultrasonic sensor for wireless monitoring of intracranial signals</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-07334-y</link>
      <description>A bioresorbable, wireless hydrogel (metagel) sensor, encompassing both biodegradable and stimulus-responsive hydrogels for ultrasonic monitoring of intracranial signals, was implanted into intracranial space with a puncture needle and deformed in response to physiological environmental changes.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic metamaterials characterization via laser plasma sound sources</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-024-00529-w</link>
      <description>Phononic crystals and acoustic metamaterials hold great promise in advancing technology and scientific understanding of materials. Here, the authors demonstrate a characterization method for acoustic meta-structures based on broadband acoustic pulses generated by laser-plasma sound sources.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epsilon-near-zero regime for ultrafast opto-spintronics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44306-024-00025-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An autonomous design algorithm to experimentally realize three-dimensionally isotropic auxetic network structures without compromising density</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41524-024-01281-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparent radiative cooling cover window for flexible and foldable electronic displays</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-48840-x</link>
      <description>In this work, authors synthesize transparent radiative cooling cover windows for flexible and foldable electronic devices. Besides demonstrated enhanced mechanical and moisture-impermeable properties, these mitigate temperature rise of devices under solar irradiation and improve overall thermal management.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital non-Foster-inspired electronics for broadband impedance matching</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-48861-6</link>
      <description>Resonance-based systems such as electroacoustic transducers are often limited by narrow bandwidth. Here, authors report a digital non-Foster inspired circuit demonstrating significant bandwidth and power level enhancement with greater reconfigurability than conventional analog non-Foster approaches.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down-film as a new non-frame porous material for sound absorption</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-62526-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A framework for small satellite deployable structures and how to deploy them reliably</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44172-024-00210-7</link>
      <description>In a Review Article, Jonathan Sauder and colleagues develop a framework to categorize the variety of deployable structures and mechanisms available for operation on small satellites.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Droplet-based mechanical transducers modulated by the symmetry of wettability patterns</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-48538-0</link>
      <description>Asymmetric mechanical transducers are pivotal in various applications; however, conventional methods demand continuous energy and intricate fabrication. Here, the authors demonstrate a droplet-based mechanical transducer utilizing wettability-patterned surfaces, enabling precise control of droplet dynamics.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized multi-frequency nonlinear broadband piezoelectric energy harvester designs</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-61355-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically stable radiation pressure propulsion of flexible lightsails for interstellar exploration</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-47476-1</link>
      <description>Ultrathin laser-driven lightsails represent a unique vision for interstellar space exploration. Here, the authors show how spinning flexible membranes can be both shape- and trajectory-stable with multiphysics structural and nanophotonic engineering.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radiative cooling and indoor light management enabled by a transparent and self-cleaning polymer-based metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-48150-2</link>
      <description>Transparent roofs offer a solution for harnessing natural light in sustainable buildings. Here, authors demonstrate a polymer-based metamaterial with micro-pyramid surface structures that diffuses sunlight while offering passive cooling and self-cleaning properties.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust acoustic directional sensing enabled by synergy between resonator-based sensor and deep learning</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-60696-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast photoluminescence and multiscale light amplification in nanoplasmonic cavity glass</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-47539-3</link>
      <description>This article presents a unique nanocomposite plasmonic-excitonic glass with extraordinary amplified optical properties: ultra-narrow photoluminescence (FWHM = 13 nm) and ultrashort photoluminescence lifetime (90 ps) at room temperature</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origami metamaterials for ultra-wideband and large-depth reflection modulation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46907-3</link>
      <description>The researchers fuse metamaterials and origami technical to achieve ultra-wideband and large-depth reflection modulation. Flexible electronics amplify its lightweight, transparency, and cost-effectiveness, making it ideal for satellite communications.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phononic switching of magnetization by the ultrafast Barnett effect</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-07200-x</link>
      <description>Ultrafast light-induced driving of phonons at resonance in a substrate facilitates the permanent reversal of the magnetic state of a material mounted on it.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A study of analyzing longitudinal dynamic behavior of a double-rod system with longitudinal nonlinear supports</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-58986-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-photon three-dimensional printed fused silica glass with sub-micron features</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46929-x</link>
      <description>3D-printed glass holds great potential. However, it is challenging to control both the dimension and the resolution of the printed material. Here, authors present a one-photon 3D printing approach to produce high-performance fused silica glass with sub-micron resolution and millimetric dimensions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optomechanical realization of the bosonic Kitaev chain</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-07174-w</link>
      <description>We report the experimental realization of a bosonic Kitaev chain in a nano-optomechanical network.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic emission of lattice structures under cycling loading relates process parameters with fatigue properties</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44172-024-00196-2</link>
      <description>Lea Kollmannsperger and colleagues report the fatigue behaviour of additively manufactured lattice structures under cyclic loading, relating fatigue-induced properties to process characteristics using acoustic emission. The results can help to predict damage during operation through non-destructive testing.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near-zero stiffness accelerometer with buckling of tunable electrothermal microbeams</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-024-00657-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric metamaterial sandwich structure with NIM characteristics for THz imaging application</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56723-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasound generation in water via quasi-periodically snapping polymeric core–shell micro-bead excited with radiowaves</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56614-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the low-frequency band gap characteristics of longitudinal vibration of ship shafting based on bionic quasi-zero stiffness metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-89986-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: Breaking the silence - the launch of npj Acoustics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44384-025-00002-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composite acoustic system for low-frequency sound absorption</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-89151-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and modeling of a highly compact negative index floral shape metamaterial for flight navigation applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-88612-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning optimized design of THz piezoelectric perovskite-based biosensor for the detection of formalin in aqueous environments</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-88766-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On quantifying dynamic behavior of architected metal/polymer TPMS/lattices-based interpenetrating phase composites</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-84303-5</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-objective design of multi-material truss lattices utilizing graph neural networks</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-86812-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly sensitive split ring resonator-based sensor for quality monitoring of edible oils</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-85800-x</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reverse design of broadband sound absorption structure based on deep learning method</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-86077-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All-angle unidirectional flat-band acoustic metasurfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-55937-4</link>
      <description>Flat bands have empowered novel phenomena such as canalization, high-collimation and low-loss propagation. Here, the authors propose the concept of symmetry broken moiré systems, which overcomes the limitations of fixed flat bands, enabling multiple and unidirectional canalizations.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electret integrated magnetic field sensor based on magnetostrictive polymer composite with nT resolution</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-85069-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of parallel coiled cavities of different depths in microperforated panel sound absorbers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-85171-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of melt and glass states of halide perovskite semiconductors</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-024-00759-x</link>
      <description>Crystalline metal halide perovskites have garnered substantial recent research attention given their outstanding semiconducting character, unprecedented tunability and wide-range application. This Perspective highlights the exciting prospects of extending this focus beyond long-range order — that is, to glassy and melt states.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the intrinsic piezoelectric anisotropy of tetragonal ABO3 perovskites through a high-throughput study</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41524-024-01496-z</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid electromagnetic and moisture energy harvesting enabled by ionic diode films</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-55030-2</link>
      <description>Wireless energy-responsive systems are essential for intelligent devices. This study demonstrates an electromagnetic-moist coupling effect for energy harvesting and signal transmission using fabricated ionic diode films, showing improved performance and potential for practical applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimaterial cryogenic printing of three-dimensional soft hydrogel machines</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-55323-6</link>
      <description>Hydrogel-based machines have potential in a range of applications, but it can be challenging to prepare multimaterial devices with complex structures. Here, the authors report the development of a multimaterial cryogenic printing technique that can be used to prepare three-dimensional structures with geometries such as overhanging, thin-walled and hollow.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of nickel and copper shells on mechanical properties of advanced lightweight TPU metamaterials during uniaxial compression</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-82317-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the digital–physical divide using haptic and wearable technologies</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-024-01325-7</link>
      <description>This Review examines the development of haptic and wearable technologies that could be used to build a more realistic and immersive metaverse, exploring the potential applications of such technology and the ethical and technological challenges that the field faces.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heavy-boundary mode patterning and dynamics of topological phonons in polymer chains and supramolecular lattices on surfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-54511-8</link>
      <description>Topological phonon boundary modes (TBM) hold promises for advanced phononic applications. Here, the authors introduce the bulk-heavy boundary correspondence to pattern TBM in polymers and supramolecular assemblies under thermal fluctuations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanics of Drosophila wing deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-54527-0</link>
      <description>Upon emerging from their pupal case, insects swiftly deploy their wings from a compact origami-like structure to a fully extended blade. Here, authors use a combination of imaging and mechanical tests to model the kinematics and dynamics of wing deployment in Drosophila.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives of chiral nanophotonics: from mechanisms to biomedical applications</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44310-024-00045-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomimetic optoelectronics with nanomaterials for artificial vision</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-024-00750-6</link>
      <description>Inspired by biological systems, artificial vision technologies have advanced considerably, particularly with the development of curved image sensors, which improve visual data capture, and neuromorphic optoelectronics, which enable efficient in-sensor processing. This Review provides a comprehensive discussion of current nanomaterial-based biomimetic optoelectronics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial-based Artificial magnetic conductor for efficient breast cancer diagnosis using a low-cost antenna array</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-79666-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal imaging through hot emissive windows</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44172-024-00316-y</link>
      <description>It is not currently possible for an infrared camera to see through a hot window. Now Ciril Samuel Prasad and colleagues report a metasurface-coated window which suppresses thermal emission towards an IR camera while being sufficiently transparent for thermal imaging.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust liquid crystal semi-interpenetrating polymer network with superior energy-dissipation performance</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-54233-x</link>
      <description>The design of liquid crystal networks as energy dissipation materials achieving simultaneously good mechanical and energy dissipation properties is challenging. Here, the authors fabricate energy-dissipation liquid crystal semi-interpenetrating polymer networks consisting liquid crystalline polymers with synergistic properties.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel gyroscope based on the slow surface acoustic wave in a phononic metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41378-024-00787-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the directionality of membrane coupled Helmholtz resonators under open air conditions</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-79568-9</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadband surface enhanced infrared absorption with multiple Fano resonance by metallic oblique-wire-bundle metamaterial absorbers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-78633-7</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model analysis and experiment study for effects of thermal viscous and fluid flow on ventilated acoustic metamaterials labyrinth</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-78454-8</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-performance ultra-compact plasmonic metamaterial structure for optical THz absorption</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-77898-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing the topological pentagon states of a giant C540 metamaterial</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-53819-9</link>
      <description>Fullerenes possess unique electronic property influenced by their real space topology and gauge field. Here, the authors construct an acoustic C540 fullerene metamaterial, allowing observation of 3D topological pentagon states using sound waves, and offering new insights into classical wave manipulation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Localized topological states beyond Fano resonances via counter-propagating wave mode conversion in piezoelectric microelectromechanical devices</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-53925-8</link>
      <description>The authors introduce a MEMS device that leverages the destructive interference between two topological radiofrequency (RF) counter-propagating wave modes at a piezoelectric Aluminum Scandium Nitride (AlScN) Su-Schrieffer-Heeger (SSH) interface. This device offers enhanced sensing capabilities compared to conventional NEMS/MEMS, particularly for localized parameters such as the mass of a single cell.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating new materials by turning failure on its head</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-03599-5</link>
      <description>Usually, materials either are stiff or can absorb shocks or vibrations; they rarely achieve both. A fresh approach combines these seemingly incompatible properties in materials that are at once stiff, lightweight and shock-absorbent. This technique embraces the failure of the materials.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandgap characteristics of four component periodic pile barriers in passive vibration isolation</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-76735-w</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the study of solitary wave dynamics and interaction phenomena in the ultrasound imaging modelled by the fractional nonlinear system</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-75494-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overdamping of vibration resonances by liquid crystal elastomers</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-76952-3</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring smart hydrogels through manipulation of heterogeneous subdomains</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-53552-3</link>
      <description>Replicating the cellular structures in soft tissue has promise in the design of soft materials. Here, the authors report a hydrogel system with cellular patterns in which strain-driven heterogeneous subdomains are induced, allowing local and global behaviour to be tuned.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamaterial biosensors for driver monitoring</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-024-01266-1</link>
      <description>Monitoring driver alertness could improve road safety, but the use of biosensors in moving vehicles is challenging. Now, a metamaterial biosensor has been designed that can be directly embroidered onto seat belts, enabling the contactless measurement of drivers’ vital signs. This biosensor shows reliable and consistent performance, even in challenging kinetic environments.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neo-Hookean modeling of nonlinear coupled behavior in circular plates supported by micro-pillars</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-76528-1</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable heat harvesting via thermal nonlinearity</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42254-024-00771-8</link>
      <description>This Perspective surveys the role of thermal nonlinearity in figures of merit through a multiscale physical understanding to advance heat harvesting technologies beyond linear processes, focusing on ‘nonlinear heat harvesting’, which potentially contributes to sustainable energy transition and decarbonization goals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandgap formation mechanism in tacticity inspired elastic mechanical metastructures</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-75462-6</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A digitally embroidered metamaterial biosensor for kinetic environments</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-024-01263-4</link>
      <description>A textile metamaterial sensor can wirelessly measure biomarkers—such as heart rate and respiration—in vehicles and shows no accuracy degradation when operating in moving environments.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-chip phonon-enhanced IR near-field detection of molecular vibrations</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-53182-9</link>
      <description>Phonon polaritons can be harnessed for SEIRA spectroscopy. Here, the authors demonstrate a compact on-chip phononic SEIRA platform based on a h-BN/graphene/h-BN heterostructure atop a metal split-gate that serves both as a SEIRA substrate and as a room-temperature infrared detector.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-functional programmable active acoustic meta-device: acoustic switch, lens, and barrier</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-71737-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separating, purifying and decoding elastic waves by mimicking a cochlea on a thin plate</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01818-z</link>
      <description>Cochlea is a high-resolution auditory transduction organ to distinguish sounds in both high sensitivity and broadband working frequency. The authors mimic a cochlea on a plate, which can separate, purify and decode complicated elastic waves in quite a compact way.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and architecting of a broadband bullet-diamond shaped integrated frequency selective meta-surface absorber for aero-stealth platform</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-71559-0</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composite metastructure with tunable ultra-wide low-frequency three-dimensional band gaps for vibration and noise control</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-73909-4</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active encoding of flexural wave with non-diffractive Talbot effect</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-73189-y</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated discovery of reprogrammable nonlinear dynamic metamaterials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-024-02008-6</link>
      <description>A framework is presented to automate the design of flexible metamaterial structures that can execute desired nonlinear dynamic tasks and have reprogrammable functionality.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic response of sandwich functionally graded nanoplate under thermal environments and elastic foundations using dynamic stiffness method</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-70210-2</link>
      <description>No summary</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
